Pay attention. Pain plus reflection
注意。 痛苦加上反思
equals progress. And from that
等于进步。 正是基于这一
principle, my company became the largest
原则，我的公司成为了
hedge fund in the world.
世界上最大的对冲基金。
&gt;&gt; Managing how much?
管理多少？
&gt;&gt; $150 billion. But I learned that history
1500亿美元。 但我了解到，了解那些
of things that never happened in my
在我有生之年从未发生过的历史事件，
understand in order to predict the
对于预测
future. And we can get into that if you
未来至关重要。 如果你愿意，我们可以深入探讨一下
want.
。
&gt;&gt; Peace.
和平。
&gt;&gt; Ray Dallio is the legendary billionaire
雷·达利奥是一位传奇的亿万富翁
investor
投资者，
&gt;&gt; who decoded the cycles of human history
他破解了人类历史的周期规律，
to predict financial crashes. build the
从而预测了金融危机。 打造
world's largest hedge fund.
全球最大的对冲基金。
&gt;&gt; And now to warn us about what lies
现在，我要警告大家即将面临的情况
ahead.
。
&gt;&gt; Are you optimistic about the future of
你对英国的未来持乐观态度吗
the UK?
？
&gt;&gt; No.
不。那
&gt;&gt; What about the United States?
美国呢？
&gt;&gt; Why?
不。
&gt;&gt; Okay. In order to bet on what's going to
为什么？
happen on the global economy, I learned
全球经济的未来走向，我了解到
that there's five big forces that create
有五大力量创造了
a big cycle that's repeated through
一个在历史上不断重复的大周期，这个周期
history which lasts about 80 years. The
大约持续 80 年。
first is the money debt force that
第一种力量是金钱债务，它
creates wealth and opportunities gaps
造成了财富和机会的差距，
and it's connected to the second force,
它与第二种力量——
the internal conflict where you don't
内部冲突——有关，在这种冲突中，人们不
trust the system causing wars between
信任体制，导致左右两派之间的战争，
the left and the right and it's not easy
而像向
answers like tax the rich and we can get
富人征税这样的简单解决办法并不多，我们可以深入
into that. But the third is geopolitical
探讨这个问题。 但第三个因素是地缘政治
force. In other words, international
力量。 换句话说，就是国际
conflict. Then there's acts of nature.
冲突。 此外，还有自然灾害。
And then number five is man's
第五点是人类的
inventiveness particularly of new
创造力，尤其是在新
technologies. Now the question is who
技术方面。 现在的问题是，谁将
wins the technology war because the
赢得这场科技战争，因为
winner of that determine how the new
这场战争的赢家将决定新世界
world order works.
秩序的运作方式。
&gt;&gt; Is it something to be concerned about?
这值得担心吗？
&gt;&gt; No. The question is how you as an
不，问题在于你
individual handle it.
个人如何应对。
&gt;&gt; How do I as an individual handle it?
作为个人，我应该如何应对？
&gt;&gt; So there's building your financial
所以，关键在于增强你的财务
strength, flexibility, the importance of
实力、保持灵活性、
being open-minded and how to get more
保持开放的心态以及如何更好地利用
out of the minute, not how to work
每一分钟，而不是如何更
harder. And I really urge your audience
努力地工作。 我强烈建议您的听众
to learn all of this. So, first of all,
学习所有这些内容。 首先，
&gt;&gt; I see messages all the time in the
我经常在
comment section that some of you didn't
评论区看到有人留言说他们没有
realize you didn't subscribe. So, if you
意识到自己没有订阅。 所以，如果您
could do me a favor and double check if
能帮我个忙，再次确认一下
you're a subscriber to this channel,
您是否是本频道的订阅者，我
that would be tremendously appreciated.
将万分感激。
It's the simple, it's the free thing
这是件简单又免费的事情，
that anybody that watches this show
任何经常观看本节目的人都
frequently can do to help us here to
可以做，以帮助我们
keep everything going in this show in
保持本节目目前的良好发展
the trajectory it's on. So, please do
势头。 所以，请您
double check if you've subscribed and uh
再次确认是否已订阅，
thank you so much because in a strange
非常感谢，因为从某种意义上说
way, you are you're part of our history
，您是我们历史的一部分，
and you're on this journey with us and I
您与我们一起踏上了这段旅程，我
appreciate you for that. So, yeah, thank
为此感谢您。 是的，
you.
谢谢。
[Music]
[音乐]
Ray,
雷，
I I want to describe to you who's
我想向
listening right now. And the question I
现在正在收听的各位描述一下。 我想问
have for you is what is the most
你的问题是，在这个最高层面上，
important thing that this persona of
这个
person should be thinking about at the
人最应该思考的是什么
highest level right now. So the person
。 所以，正在
that's listening is someone who is
听的人是想要
intent on improving their life. They're
改善自己生活的人。 他们
they're really interested in business,
对商业非常感兴趣，
potentially starting their own business.
有可能自己创业。
They they care about where they're
他们关心自己把
investing their their time and energy
时间和精力投入到哪里，
and also where they're setting up their
也关心自己
home based on in terms of geography.
根据地理位置在哪里安家落户。
They are aspiring to accomplish some
他们渴望实现某个
goal. They're probably between the age
目标。 他们年龄可能
of 18 and 50 predominantly and they are
主要在 18 岁到 50 岁之间，他们
very very interested in understanding
非常非常想了解
fast-paced and uncertain at the moment.
目前这个令人感到无比恐惧、节奏飞快且充满不确定性的世界正在发生什么。
This is a very difficult question, but
这是一个非常棘手的问题，但
if anyone I was going to ask anyone, it
如果非要问谁，那
would have to be you. What What's one of
只能是你了。
considering at this moment to safeguard
为了保障
their future, their family, their
他们的未来、家庭和
finances?
财务安全，他们此刻首先应该考虑的是什么？
&gt;&gt; I don't think it's a difficult question.
我觉得这不是个难题。
I um I think it's it's very clear. They
嗯，我觉得这很清楚。 他们
have to understand how the life cycle
必须了解生命周期是如何
works. Okay? They have to understand it
运作的。 好的？ 他们必须了解它的
how it works. We were just talking
运作原理。 我们
before, you know, in the book and there
之前还在讨论，你知道，在书里，提到了
was the arc of the life cycle, right?
生命周期的弧线，对吧？
And you have to understand that you're
你必须明白，你正在
on an adventurous journey. Okay? And you
踏上一段冒险之旅。 好的？ 你
have a certain nature.
有一种独特的性格。
You know, those qualities that ma make
你知道，那些特质会让
you have your preferences and so on. And
你产生自己的偏好等等。
then you're going after the things that
然后，你就会去追求
you like and you're learning and it's
你喜欢的东西，你会不断学习，这其中会有
going to have the ups and downs and so
起起伏伏
on and how you approach that. So you
等等，关键在于你如何应对。 所以你
asked from the higher level if I'm
从更高的层面提问，如果我从
looking down you know like that life
下方观察，你知道，就像生命
cycle that arc what's that journey like
周期的弧线，那段旅程是怎样的？
how do you approach it you know what are
你如何看待它？
your principles how do you even learn
你的原则是什么？你如何学习
how to approach it that's why we're
如何看待它？这就是我们进行
having these conversations right y
这些对话的原因，对吧？
&gt;&gt; so that's clear you know what's your
所以很清楚，你知道你的本性是什么，
nature how's the journey how do you find
旅程是怎样的，你如何找到
the path that's suitable to your nature
适合你本性的道路，
&gt;&gt; and then you'll go down that path and
然后你沿着那条路走下去，
you'll discover
你会发现，
and you'll evolve. What's that like?
你会进化。 那是什么感觉？
That's what they need to know.
这就是他们需要知道的。
&gt;&gt; You said what's your nature? What do you
你问你的本性是什么？ 你说的“
mean by nature?
自然”指的是什么？
&gt;&gt; People are born with and then also their
人天生具有某种性格，而
environment creates their different
环境也会塑造其不同的
nature. You know, we have our
性格。 你知道，我们都有自己的
preferences, our inclinations. We think
喜好和倾向。 我们
in a certain way. You chose to be
以某种特定的方式思考。 你选择了
entrepreneurial. Okay? You're living out
创业。 好的？ 你这是在活出
your nature. Okay? This isn't for
你的本性。 好的？ 这不是给
somebody else. You know, some people
别人的。 你知道，有些人
have a different nature. Okay? They
天性不同。 好的？ 他们
would like to have the stability of a
想要一份稳定的
job and clarity and so on. So when you
工作和清晰的规划等等。 所以，当你
have your nature, you want to know that
了解了自己的天性之后，你会想要知道这一点，
and then find the path that is going to
然后找到适合
be good for your nature. Then there's
自己天性的道路。 然后还有一些
the particular tactical stuff. So if you
具体的战术方面的内容。 所以如果你
would ask me, should I be in the UK or
问我，我应该留在英国还是
should I be in the US? Well, that
应该留在美国？ 这
depends on a lot of things, but that's a
取决于很多因素，但这是一个
tactical question.
战术问题。
&gt;&gt; So if I want to be an entrepreneur and I
所以，如果我想成为一名企业家，并
want to build a technology company, do
想创办一家科技公司，
you think I should be in the UK or the
你认为我应该在英国还是
US? I think you should be in the US.
美国？ 我认为你应该待在美国。
&gt;&gt; Why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; The US has a culture of um
美国有着浓厚的
entrepreneurship, inventiveness. There's
创业和创新文化。
a whole different culture like in Europe
欧洲整体文化与英国截然不同，
generally speaking and in and in the UK
英国有
there's an establishment culture, right?
一种根深蒂固的体制文化，对吧？
And here um you could be 25, have a blue
嗯，你可能25岁，头发里挑染了一缕蓝色，
but if you got the talent to pull it
但你有才华，如果你有才能
off, you can get the resources and you
，你就能获得资源，你
can be an entrepreneur. It's there's a
就能成为一名企业家。 那里存在一种
culture of that. That means that it's
文化。 这意味着这种情况
happening more. That's why you even see
发生的频率越来越高。 这就是为什么你会看到各国
the differences in the economies. Okay,
经济存在差异的原因。 好吧，
where is the inventiveness really
真正的创造力
happening? Okay, it's happening here. So
体现在哪里呢？ 好了，事情正在这里发生。 所以
I would say if you want to be an
我觉得，如果你想成为一名
entrepreneur, this is an environment
企业家，这里的环境
that's particularly conducive to being
特别有利于你成为
an entrepreneur.
企业家。
&gt;&gt; So what is your honest perspective about
那么，你对英国目前的状况有什么真实看法
the UK at the moment?
？
&gt;&gt; The UK has a financial problem. Uh the
英国面临财政问题。 呃，
government has a debt problem and it
政府有债务问题，而且
doesn't have enough money for what it
没有足够的资金来实现它
wants to do and what it can do. And so
想做的事情和它能做的事情。 所以
what you see is the nondom problem,
你看到的就是非居民问题，
people moving and so on so forth. And
人口流动等等。
throughout history, when you have these
纵观历史，每当出现这类
sorts of things, then there's great
事情时，
clashes in people. Okay? And the UK has
人们之间就会发生巨大的冲突。 好的？ 自
been in decline since the war. Even the
二战以来，英国一直处于衰落状态。 即使是
development of the capital markets, can
资本市场的发展，
you raise capital there? All of these
你也能在那里筹集资金吗？ 所有这些
things are much worse than they are in
情况都比美国糟糕得多
the United States.
。   这会
&gt;&gt; And it leads to clashes. He said,
导致冲突。 他说：
&gt;&gt; "Of course, you know, there are five big
“当然，你知道，有五大
forces that create a big cycle that
力量构成了一个
about 80 years, give or take 50, let's
大约持续80年（上下浮动50年）的大周期
say. And the five big forces are there's
。这五大力量分别是：
a money,
货币、
debt, economy force, okay? Debts are
债务和经济力量。债务代表
spending power. So what happens is when
消费能力。当
you give somebody credit they can spend
你给别人信贷时，他们就可以消费，
and then but it also produces debt and
但这也会产生债务，而
debt has to be paid back and so what
债务必须偿还。
happens is if there's not enough income
如果收入不足以
to pay back the debt then you have um
偿还债务，那么
debt rising relative to income it
债务相对于收入就会上升，这会
squeezes out spending people don't want
挤压消费，人们不愿
to hold the debt assets and so on the UK
持有债务资产，等等。英国
has gone through that and has gone
已经经历过这种情况，而且
through that and it's connected to the
这种情况与
second force And we're all going through
第二股力量有关。我们都在
this in varying degrees. The second
不同程度上经历着这种力量。第二股
force is the internal political and
力量是内部的政治和
social force. In other words, like
社会力量。换句话说，就像
between the left and the right with
左右两派之间的
wealth gaps and opportunities gaps. We
财富差距和机会差距一样。我们
have big wealth and opportunities gaps.
存在巨大的财富和机会差距。
So when you have big wealth and
所以，当财富和
opportunities gaps, there's conflict.
机会差距巨大时，就会出现冲突。左右两派
Okay? Conflict between the left and the
之间的冲突。
right. And when you get to the situation
当这种情况发生时……” 如果
where you don't believe the system is
你不相信这个体系
working for you and you don't trust the
对你有利，也不信任这个
system, then there are wars. There are
体系，那么就会爆发战争。由此会引发
internal conflicts over over that and so
内部冲突等等
on. So the third force is the
。所以，第三种力量是地
geopolitical force. In other words, u
缘政治力量。换句话说，
there's a cycle that usually goes from
通常会有一个循环，
one big war to another big war. So the
一场大战接着一场大战。上
last war ended in 194544
一场战争结束于1944年，
and we began a new order in 1945. And
我们在1945年开启了一个新的秩序。这个秩序的
the way that works is that the winners
运作方式是，
of the war determine how the world order
战争的胜利者决定世界秩序的
works. They draw borders. They say
运作方式。他们划定边界，宣布世界秩序的
here's how it's going to work. And
运作方式。
that's the new order. Okay? And that
这就是新的秩序。明白吗？这种情况会一直持续下去，
continues until there's a rising power
直到一个新兴强权
challenging an existing power and the
挑战现有的强权和
existing world order which typically is
现有的世界秩序，而此时现有的世界秩序通常正在
deteriorating at that time. And then you
瓦解。然后就会
have international conflict. Okay, these
出现国际冲突。这些
orders, there's a monetary order, they
秩序，比如货币秩序，都会
all break down. There's an in internal
崩溃；内部
political order, they all break down.
政治秩序，也会崩溃；还有地缘
And and there's a geopolitical order.
政治秩序，它们之间
work together. The fourth force
相互影响，彼此冲突。
throughout history has been acts of
纵观历史，第四种力量是
nature. Droughts, floods, and pandemics,
自然灾害。 例如，干旱、洪水和流行病造成的死亡
for example, have killed more people
人数超过了
than wars. And acts of nature, nature
战争。自然灾害，自然的
has a big effect. And then number five
影响巨大。第五个
force is man's inventiveness
因素是人类的创造力，
particularly of new technologies.
特别是新技术的创造。
Okay, because if you see that
因为这种
inventiveness that has raised per capita
创造力提高了人均
incomes, GDP per capita, any measures of
收入、人均GDP以及
living standards over a period of time
一段时间内衡量生活水平的各项指标
and and so on. But it is also related to
等等。但它也与
the first four that I said those four
我提到的前四个因素相关，这
four forces interact. Now when we go
四个因素相互作用。现在我们
back to your UK case, okay, they have a
回到英国的例子，他们面临着
financial problem.
财政问题。
they and almost every country now is
他们和几乎所有国家一样，现在都
for the same reasons. Wealth gaps,
因为同样的原因面临着更多的内部政治问题。财富差距、
opportunities gaps, what do we do? Who's
机会差距，我们该怎么办？谁
got the power? I don't trust the system
掌握权力？我不信任这个体制
kind of thing. Okay. Number three is we
等等。第三个因素是我们
are certainly in an international great
无疑正处于一场国际大
powers conflict, right? And it certainly
国冲突之中，对吧？这无疑会
affects Europe and the UK as we're
影响欧洲和英国，因为我们
dealing with not only the Ukraine
不仅要应对乌克兰
situation but the Russian situation and
局势，还要应对俄罗斯局势，这
what does that mean and that relates to
意味着什么？这与
the money thing because okay where's the
资金问题有关，因为
money coming from to have defense or
国防或
military expenditures and so on so
军事开支的资金从哪里来？ 支出
forth. So that matters right the
等等。所以，地缘
geopolitical matters climate certainly
政治因素很重要，气候当然也很
matters and then of course technology
重要，当然还有科技和
man's inventiveness.
人类的创造力。
So everything could be looked through at
所以，一切都可以
through that lens.
从这个角度来看待。
&gt;&gt; And so what does this mean for the UK if
那么，如果
all other countries are going through
其他国家也都在经历
this as well? Doesn't that just mean
这一切，这对英国意味着什么呢？这难道不意味着
that all countries are going to suffer
所有国家都会遭受
equally?
同样的损失吗？
&gt;&gt; No. No. No. Because they're not all
不，不，不。因为它们并不
equal. Okay. Some are more in debt than
相同。有些国家比其他国家负债更多
others. Okay. Some people are more
。有些人
willing to hold their debt than others.
比其他人更愿意偿还债务。有些国家
Um some means they they have more
拥有更多
resources. Some are bigger and more
资源。有些国家更大更
powerful. Some are less powerful.
强大。有些国家则相对弱小。
They're different. Okay. They're all go
它们各不相同。它们都
in different conditions. Some countries
处于不同的境况。有些国家
have surpluses. Some countries, you
有盈余。有些国家，你
know, are not in the middle of where
知道，没有卷入
there's having a war.
战争。
&gt;&gt; Are you optimistic about the the future
你目前对英国的未来持乐观态度吗
of the UK at the moment?
？
&gt;&gt; No,
不，
no.
不。
&gt;&gt; Because it has high debt. It has the
因为它负债累累。它存在
social internal conflict. It it's
社会内部冲突。它受到地缘
affected by the geopolitical factors.
政治因素的影响。
And in terms of inventiveness, it
而且就创造力而言，它
doesn't have the culture that other
不像其他国家那样拥有独特的文化。
countries have like like the US. Is that
就像美国那样。是
&gt;&gt; Yes. The cult culture and the capital
的。那种狂热的文化和
markets to support that at a scale that
支撑这种文化的资本市场，其规模之大，
it needs to be supported to play
足以让它
seriously in the game.
在竞争中占据一席之地。
&gt;&gt; And for anyone that doesn't know capital
对于不了解资本
markets mean basically the investor
市场的人来说，它基本上就是投资者
markets is way of saying
市场，简单来说就是
&gt;&gt; well I mean it gets you the money. In
它能给你带来资金。
other words, you're a guy with you know
换句话说，你是一个有钱人，你知道接下来会发生什么，那就是
&gt;&gt; we have to enable people. Okay. What
我们需要赋能他人。好的。有效的
what works is finding great people,
方法是找到优秀的人才
talented people, and identifying those
，找到
who you want to bet on and enabling
你想投资的人，并赋能
them. And that works. That's the most
他们。这确实有效。这是最
important force, much more important
重要的力量，
than money. Okay? Because you could see
远比金钱重要。好吗？因为你可以看到
who's got the money and power and where
谁拥有金钱和权力，以及
did they come from? Where did Nvidia
他们来自哪里？英伟达是从哪里起家的
come from? Where did where did they all
？他们都
come from? Okay? There are guys like
来自哪里？好吗？像
you, entrepreneur in a sense, who's been
你这样的人，某种意义上的企业家，得到了
enabled, okay, by you because you have
赋能，好吗？因为你有
the talent and people want to bet on you
才华，人们想投资你，
and that's the capital market. So they
这就是资本市场。所以他们
give you money to help enable you
给你钱来帮助你，
because they want to bet on you and then
因为他们想投资你，然后
good things happen.
好事就发生了。
&gt;&gt; But are you are you optimistic about the
但是你对
United States at the moment?
美国的未来乐观吗？ 目前来看？
&gt;&gt; The United States is very much a big
美国的情况很大程度上取决于
picture. No, I think it's very much in
大局。不，我认为
this issue there. So, if I go down my
这个问题确实存在。所以，如果我逐一
list, it definitely has this uh debt
分析，它肯定存在债务
money economy problem. We can get into
货币经济问题。我们可以深入探讨一下
that. Okay. It definitely has the
。好的。它肯定存在
internal conflict power in which there's
内部权力冲突，
a fight between the left, you know, the
左翼（
hard left and the right due to wealth
极左翼）和右翼之间存在斗争，这是由于财富
and values gaps and people not believing
和价值观的差距造成的，人们不相信
that the system will work for them. And
这个体制会为他们服务。
so democracy is at risk because they
因此，民主面临风险，因为他们
don't believe this. They they're not
不相信这一点。他们不会
going to follow the rules in the sense
遵守规则，因为他们
they don't believe the rules are going
不相信规则会有效。
to uh number three it's of course the
第三点，它当然是
conflict of the world right in other
世界大国冲突中的主导方，对吧？
words yes between the United States and
换句话说，是的，美国和
the one side let's say and China and the
中国及其
allies their allies on the other side. I
盟友之间的冲突。我的
mean in the news you just saw the
意思是，你刚才在新闻里看到了
meetings of Xi Putin Modi and that group
习近平、普京、莫迪以及那边那群人的会晤。
okay so now it should be pretty clear
好的，现在应该很清楚
how the sides are lining up okay you
各方的立场了。好的，
it's always better to be in a place
总是要站在…… 一个
that's not in one of those wars like
不卷入战争的地方，比如
stay out of wars um and of course
远离战争，当然，
climate has an effect and of course then
气候也有影响，当然还有
we have technology the United States and
科技。美国和
China are in the big technology compet
中国正在进行大规模的科技
competitions. The others are really not
竞争。其他国家实际上并没有
in the game. They don't have the money
参与其中。他们没有足够的资金、
that this innovation and talent in a
创新能力和人才来
sense to play at that scale and so on.
参与这种规模的竞争等等。
So we have a great you know technology
所以我们面临着一场巨大的科技
war which can be used to create great
战争，这场战争既可以带来巨大的
advances but at the same time could be
进步，也可能
used for great conflicts. And so now the
引发巨大的冲突。所以现在的
question is going to be who wins the
问题是，谁会赢得这场
technology war because the winner of the
科技战争？因为
technology war is going to win all wars.
科技战争的赢家将赢得所有战争。
Okay. In other words, they'll win the
换句话说，他们将赢得
economic war. They'll win the
经济战争，赢得地缘
geopolitical war because technology and
政治战争，因为科技——
I'm not saying anything that hasn't
我说的这些
repeated through history.
在历史上都曾重演过。
&gt;&gt; Give me that historical context if you
如果你能提供一些历史背景，就科技而言，
&gt;&gt; the technology for example nuclear.
比如核武器。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的，
&gt;&gt; Nuclear
核武器
won World War II.
赢得了第二次世界大战。
&gt;&gt; And and does this cycle go back further
这种循环是否比这更早？
than just
哦，不，它比那本书里提到的还要早。好的。
Um, in order to understand these things,
嗯，为了理解这些，
cuz I have to bet on what's going to
因为我必须…… 押注未来会
happen. I'm a global macro investor. I
发生什么。我是一名全球宏观投资者。我
study the last 500 years of history and
研究过去500年的历史，发现这种情况
and it happens over and over again in
在
all cases.
所有案例中反复出现。
So, I could take the British Empire, I
所以，我可以以大英帝国为例，我
could take you through all the empires,
可以带你回顾所有帝国，包括
the Dutch Empire before that, and all
之前的荷兰帝国等等，这种情况一直在
this, and it it it happens uh all the
发生
time. I watched your I watched your
。我看过你
videos about this and it was truly
关于这方面的视频，
fascinating how predictable this stuff
这些事情的可预测性
is and the work that you've done to
以及你为
uncover this trend throughout history. I
揭示历史趋势所做的工作真的令人着迷。我的
mean, it's almost for me it was almost
意思是，对我
I think it's like a 40-minute video on
来说，观看你在YouTube上发布的那个大约40分钟的视频，几乎是无可辩驳的证据，
YouTube where you show how this played
你在视频中展示了这种现象
out through empires. And it begs the
在各个帝国中是如何体现的。这引出了一个
question, you know, because when you
问题，你知道，当你
live in the United States, when you're
生活在美国，当
when you're in the present time, you
你身处当今时代，你
almost never assume that the empire
几乎从不认为
you're in could fall. You just don't you
你所在的帝国会衰落。你就是
don't see how it could happen. We're so
看不到它会发生。我们如此
strong. We're so great, you know, we're
强大，如此伟大，你知道，我们如此……
so that doing AI over here, have money
人工智能在这里，金钱
over here, everything's good, the sun's
在这里，一切都很好，阳光
shining.
明媚。
&gt;&gt; It's inconceivable.
这简直难以置信。
&gt;&gt; Of course, people always think that the
当然，人们总是认为
future would be a slightly modified
未来会是
version of the present, and it's not.
现在的略微修改版，但事实并非如此。
Okay. Watch over decades, but it's like
好吧。观察几十年，就像
watching a person grow.
观察一个人的成长。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。好吧
&gt;&gt; Okay.
。是的
&gt;&gt; You know, you watch your kid or you
你知道，你观察你的孩子，或者
watch a person at your age, any age, and
观察一个和你同龄的人，任何年龄的人，
that's what you see.
你看到的就是这些。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Okay. And you don't see the life
。好吧。你看不到人生的
arc.
轨迹。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。好吧
&gt;&gt; Okay. But the life arc is in
。但人生的轨迹是
irrefutable.
无可辩驳的。
&gt;&gt; But the U do you think it's conceivable
但是，你认为
that in the next 50 to 100 years the US
在未来50到100年内，美国
could no longer be the dominant power
有可能不再是全球主导力量吗
globally?
？是的。是的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. More than conceivable.
完全有可能。
What does what do you mean by more than
你说的“完全有可能”是什么意思
conceivable?
？
I mean that these evolutions always take
我的意思是，这些演变总是会
place and they take place in a certain
发生，而且它们以某种
way and that um if you look at the
方式发生，如果你看看
probabilities
概率、
um and the paths and the symptoms
路径和迹象，就会发现
there is a challenge the United States
美国正面临着一个挑战。 面临
is facing a number of those challenges
诸多挑战，
and we're at a moment where Um it's a
而我们现在正处于一个关键时刻：
question of whether the system and
体制和
the people
民众
could can get control
能否掌控
of the situations and deal with it
局面，并以一种既能有效应对又不至于
damaging each other and damaging
互相争斗、损害彼此利益、破坏
managing the prospects for the future.
未来前景的方式来应对。
&gt;&gt; But I mean, the United States is very
我的意思是，美国极具
innovative. Got all these great
创新精神，拥有众多优秀的
innovative companies here. So surely
创新型公司。所以，当然，是
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But you you can't make
的。但是，你不能
generalizations about the United States.
对美国妄下断言。
And you can't make generalizations, by
顺便说一句，你也不能
the way, about the markets either.
对市场妄下断言。
population if you're looking at the
如果你查看
breakdown of incomes and also you're
收入构成，以及
looking at the innovation the stock
创新、股市、
markets which stocks are doing well who
哪些股票表现良好、谁
owns those companies and all of that
拥有这些公司等等所有这些信息，你会发现，
about three million people in a country
在一个拥有3.3亿人口的国家里，只有大约1%的人——占总人口的1%——取得了令人
unbelievably doing great and you could
难以置信的成就。你可以
pick the neighborhoods they're in and
指出他们所在的社区以及
what they're doing. And then there's the
他们的工作内容。然后，还有
top 10%, let's say, which is the people
前10%的人，比如说，他们
around them. And they're really, really
周围的人。 他们。而且他们
doing great in that world. At the same
在那个世界里真的做得非常出色。
time, the bottom 60%
与此同时，
60% of Americans have below a sixth
美国底层60%的人
grade reading level.
阅读水平低于六年级。
&gt;&gt; Wow.
哇。就
in terms of um the basics
基本的
being productive,
生产力而言，这部分人口
you have to be productive and be
必须具备生产力和
prosperous. So what what you need to
繁荣。所以，
have a su successful society is to have
一个成功的社会需要
broadbased productivity and prosperity.
广泛的生产力和繁荣。
Okay? And that's a problem.
明白吗？而这正是一个问题。
Okay? So, which America are you looking
明白吗？那么，你关注的是哪个美国
at? And are you watching the war that's
？你是否在关注
happening between these?
这些群体之间正在发生的冲突？
&gt;&gt; It's a little bit complicated for me as
作为一个局外人，这对我来说有点复杂，
a as a bit of an outsider because I see
因为我看到
Trump saying he represents those people,
特朗普说他代表这些人，
but obviously Trump is a from the
但显然特朗普
billionaire class himself. So, I mean,
本人也来自亿万富翁阶层。所以，我的意思是，
is he is he a savior for inequality? Is
他是解决不平等的救世主吗？
he correcting? I think I think he sees a
他是在纠正吗？我认为他看到了
lot of the problem and he uh I think he
很多问题，他
sees the debt problem. I think he sees
看到了债务问题，我认为他看到了
the internal conflict disorder problem
内部冲突和混乱问题，
and I think he represents
我认为他代表的是
uh the red, let's call it the red
红色州，我们姑且称之为红色
states. I mean, you look at a map and
州。我的意思是，你 看看地图，
there's red and blue and you see where
上面有红色和蓝色，你看
they are, okay? And he represents that
它们分别在哪里，好吗？他代表了红色和蓝色，
and they're united behind him in terms
他们团结在他周围，共同
of doing some things. Okay? So he
做一些事情。好吗？所以他
represents let's call it the red side
代表着我们称之为“红色阵营”的一方，
which is located where the maps shows
地图上
red and then there are the blue and and
红色区域就是蓝色区域。
he's um he views himself as somebody who
他认为自己
needs to take charge and to do certain
需要承担责任，做某些
things. Others in that population would
事情。而那些
are having the food stamp program cut
失去食物券
off or having other programs cut off
或其他赖以生存的福利项目的人会说：“
wait a second that's not representing
等等，这不代表
me. And so we have gone that population
我。” 因此，我们看到，相当一部分人成为了
him
他的忠实拥护者，他们都支持他
&gt;&gt; that are devotees.
。
They're all in. Okay. At the same time
与此同时，还有
as we have the other side which will
另一方，
have their devotees if you know we're in
如果你知道我们身处
New York City. Okay. And the up upcoming
纽约市，他们也有自己的拥护者。即将到来的
mayoral uh election will be an example
市长选举将是
of the two sides. Okay. And they will
双方的一次较量。他们会
try to use the system but there's a
试图利用现有的制度，但
question will the system have enough
问题是，这个制度是否有足够的
support to work. Okay. But that's what
支持来运作。 这就是
we have.
我们面临的现状。最后再谈谈
the UK in particular, if if you were to
英国的情况，如果您要
try and fix it, what would you be aiming
尝试解决这个问题，您的目标是什么
at? I say this because we do have a
？我这么说是因为英国确实存在
millionaire exodus that's widely
百万富翁外流的现象，这
reported in the UK where I think this
在英国有很多报道，我认为
year we're set to lose 16,000 roughly
今年我们将失去大约
16,000 millionaires. Um, when you look
16000名百万富翁。嗯，看看
at the big big countries like China,
中国、
America, the UAE, the UK, we're losing
美国、阿联酋和英国这些大国，我们失去的
more millionaires than anybody else. And
百万富翁比其他任何国家都多。
I was wondering if you think it's
我想知道您认为这个问题是否可以
fixable and if you were in charge of the
解决，如果您掌管
UK, what you might aim at first.
英国，您首先会着手解决什么问题？
&gt;&gt; It's diff, you know,
这很复杂，
&gt;&gt; first of all, if you go back to the
首先，如果我们回到
basic problem,
问题的根本所在，
which is there's too much debt,
那就是债务过多、
there are deficits,
财政赤字、
education and opportunity levels
教育和机会水平存在差距
and so on. The most important thing that
等等。最重要的是要有
is a strong middle.
一个强大的中间派。
&gt;&gt; Political middle.
政治中间派。
&gt;&gt; Political middle
政治中间派不仅
to be analytically strong and also
要有分析能力，还要有
strong enough to get the people to do
足够的力量去促使人们去做
what needs to be done even if they don't
应该做的事情，即使他们自己不愿意去做。
want to do it to get to be productive.
想通过这样做来提高生产力。
Now that's an easy thing to say.
说起来容易，
It's not an easy thing to do. But you do
做起来难。但你确实
need that strong middle and you do need
需要强大的中间力量，你需要让
to convey to people that you need to
人们明白，你需要强大的
have the strong middle to change
中间力量来改变
productivity
生产力。
and you know and are you in it? Are are
你知道吗？你真的身在其中吗？
you in it? Are you patriotic and in it
你爱国吗？
and you know but you look at history how
你知道吗？看看历史，
did the United States come to be the
美国是如何成为今天的
United States? People will go to the
美国的？人们会去比
places that are better than them then
自己更好的地方，而不是
stay in the places that worse for them.
留在比自己更糟的地方。
This is fundamental right
这是基本的
&gt;&gt; incentives.
激励机制。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So you have to make the place
所以你必须让这个地方变得
better.
更好。
Okay. Now I would say also you can take
现在我想说，你也可以把
pockets and they go into the pocket and
钱放进口袋，然后
let it spread out. But you also have to
让钱散播出去。但你也必须
have this equal education or you know
拥有平等的教育，或者说，
you've got to strive for equal
你必须努力争取平等的
opportunity. But anyway, it's a
机会。总之，这是一个
difficult question that I'm afraid I'm
难题，恐怕我
incapable of
无法
um solving.
解答。
your voice drop when I asked it. You
当我问这个问题时，听到你的语气低沉下来，这让我感到不安。你
seemed slightly um
似乎有点……
as if you you've kind of given up on the
好像你已经放弃了
UK a little bit. Your facial reaction?
英国。 有点儿。你的面部表情？
Well, I'm I'm just a I'm just a I'm a
嗯，我只是个务实的人，一个
practical guy.
现实的人。
I'm a realistic guy. I made my money.
我挣了钱，
I'm in the business and it's my nature
我从事这个行业，我的本性就是
to try to be realistic
尽量保持现实，
and to bet on how things will transpire.
并预测事情的发展走向。
And that's not healthy. The situation in
但这并不健康。
the UK is not healthy. And the situation
英国的现状并不健康。
in the United States is very risky in
美国的现状在
many ways. It's what we're describing.
很多方面都非常危险。这就是我们所描述的。
So, you know, and then if you look where
所以，你知道，如果你看看
are people going then then you see the
人们都去了哪里，你就会发现那些
places that have the qualities we're
具备我们所说的特质的地方
talking about. They're civil.
。它们文明，充满
They're creative.
创造力，
The people aren't at war with each
人们之间没有战争。
&gt;&gt; What happens next in history?
接下来历史会如何发展？
&gt;&gt; Well, usually there's a a big fight for
通常情况下，会有一场争夺控制权的激烈斗争
control,
，
&gt;&gt; political revolutions and things like
政治革命等等
that.
。
because they don't trust the system.
由于人们不信任这个体系，体系崩溃了。
So
那么，
will the legal system resolve that? Will
法律体系能解决这个问题吗？
the parliamentary system resolve that
议会体系能令人满意地解决
these disputes
这些争端，
to the satisfaction of those people and
让那些
the other people who have different
持有不同
points of view and the sides won't
观点的人以及其他各方都满意吗？
believe it. And this goes back
相信我。这可以追溯到
this goes back to Rome. It goes back to
罗马时代，追溯到
Caesar,
凯撒时代，追溯到
you know, the Senate. And you know this
元老院。你知道，这种现象
goes back through history all the time,
在历史上屡见不鲜，
right? And in in the 30s, four major
对吧？在20世纪30年代，四个主要的
democracies
民主国家
chose to be autocracies. Okay, that
选择了成为专制国家。这
happened in Italy, Germany, Spain, and
发生在意大利、德国、西班牙和
Japan.
日本。对于
&gt;&gt; What's autocracy for anyone that doesn't
不了解这个词的人来说，专制是什么意思呢
know the word? Well, it's it means a
？它本质上是指由
essentially of a limited number of
少数高层独裁者统治的独裁政体
people at the top who are autocratic,
，
which means that they are directing
这意味着他们掌控
things rather than a democracy
一切，而不是像民主政体那样，由
all different points of view that get
各种不同观点的代表聚集
together and follow rules to make
在一起，遵循规则做出
decisions.
决策。
So the UK could become an autocracy as
所以英国可能会变成专制国家，美国也可能变成专制国家
could the US. I guess
。我想
&gt;&gt; um you're going to see a lot of pressure
你会看到各方都迫切
for that strong leader who will get
需要一位强有力的领导人来
control of things and make it work well
掌控局面，让一切运转良好。
and will and you're likely to see two
你很可能会看到关于
different views as to which side, you
哪一方会支持哪一方的两种截然不同的观点，就像所谓的“
know, the red and the blue sides, so to
红蓝阵营”一样
speak. You're likely to see that type of
。你很可能会看到这种
clash. You said the US is playing a
冲突。你刚才提到了美国。 本身就是在玩一场
risky game itself. Is that from a de
冒险的游戏。这是从
debt perspective or otherwise
债务角度来看的，还是从其他
&gt;&gt; from these things? Okay.
方面来看的？好的。
&gt;&gt; From the debt, from the internal
从债务、内部
conflict, from the changing world order,
冲突、不断变化的世界秩序、地
the geopolitical world conflict, you
缘政治冲突来看，你
know, I don't know. We're playing with
知道，我不知道。我们在玩弄
nuclear weapons and, you know, in wars
核武器，你知道，在战争
and different places and then of course
和不同的地方，当然还有
climate and then the technology war. How
气候问题，以及科技战。
we're doing that. Yeah,
我们是怎么做到的？是的，
&gt;&gt; I saw that image the other day of Putin
前几天我看到了普京、
and um President Xi and China together
习近平主席和中国人民一起
walking together. If China does become
散步的照片。如果中国真的成为
the dominant force in the world, the
世界主导力量，
dominant power does is that a smooth
主导力量的过渡会平稳吗
transition? First of all, I don't think
？首先，我认为在
dominant power for for a very long time
很长一段时间内，任何一方都不会成为绝对的主导力量，
and and the the quickest way to have it
而最快的实现方式
is some kind of a war and that's a
就是某种战争，这很
dangerous thing and but maybe it evolves
危险。但也许情况会像
hopefully the way the Soviet Union
苏联解体那样发展，
evolved that the the worry of mutually
相互
assured destruction
确保摧毁的担忧会
keeps everybody not having that kind of
阻止各方发动那种
war and then what then then the systems
战争，然后，
one system or another system wins
某个体系或另一个体系会获胜，
but that's an evolutionary process and
但这是一个演进的过程，
you know I can't say and um
你知道，我无法断言。
&gt;&gt; do you think much about time frames
你经常思考时间框架，
because when I was watching when I was
因为当我观察
going through the changing world order
世界秩序的变迁时，我发现
predictable time frames when these these
这些转变似乎都遵循着某种一致或可预测的时间框架
transitions happen. Do you think about
。你有没有想过
where we are?
我们现在处于什么阶段？
&gt;&gt; Well, they're long-term big cycles.
嗯，这些都是长期的、大的周期。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Right. It's it's like a life cycle on
没错。这就像一个生命周期，
average they are about a life cycle
平均来说大约是
about 80 years but it's not
80年，但这并非
predetermined just like your life cycle
预先设定的，就像你的生命周期
is not predetermined like if you take
也不是预先设定的一样。如果你好好
care of yourself and you you know I
照顾自己，比如
don't know smoke eat well exercise and
不抽烟、饮食健康、锻炼
so on so forth then you will probably
等等，那么你的寿命可能会
have a longer life cycle than if you
比不注意保养的人更长。
Okay, you can see the actions and the
嗯，有点像这样。所以你会看到，在各个行业中，它们都在发展演变，但你可以看到一些征兆。你可以看到一些行为和
symptoms which like taking a physical uh
征兆，比如进行一次体检，就能
then gives you a sense of where they are
让你了解它们
in their life cycles.
处于生命周期的哪个阶段。
&gt;&gt; We're 80 years from World War II.
我们距离二战已经过去80年了。
&gt;&gt; 80 years from World War II. Yeah.
距离二战已经80年了。是的。
&gt;&gt; And you're seeing the symptoms.
你看到了这些征兆。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Symptoms are clear. They're all in
是的。征兆很明显。 所有这些都在
that book. You can see the charts of all
那本书里。你可以看到所有系统的图表
the systems.
。
&gt;&gt; if you're in the United States?
如果你在美国，这有什么好担心的吗？
No I mean, yes.
废话。我的意思是，当然有。
And then the question is how you as an
然后问题就变成了你
individual handle it.
个人该如何应对。
&gt;&gt; How do I as an individual handle it?
我个人该如何应对？
&gt;&gt; Well, first of all, I think I think you
首先，我认为你
have to be aware of the situation and
必须意识到现状以及
&gt;&gt; for me and my family though in terms of
我和我的家人面临的风险，
and how I should um counteract those
以及我应该如何应对这些
risks. Is it a case of me saving for a
风险。这是否意味着我应该
rainy day? Is it a
未雨绸缪？这其中也包含一些因素。
&gt;&gt; That's part of it. Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Um there's a there's a saying in Hong
香港有一句谚语，或者说一句
Kong um a Chinese saying which is a
中国谚语，叫做“
smart rabbit has three holes. And what
聪明的兔子有三个洞”。
that means is you can see is it the UK
它的意思是，你可以选择去英国
or the US and and I can then move to the
还是美国，然后我可以搬到
better place and get out of the place
更好的地方，离开
that's a terrible place. So can I
那个糟糕的地方。那么，我能
successfully be an immigrant or whatever
成功地成为一名移民，或者
and change my location? throughout
改变我的居住地吗？纵观
history that's been important. So the
历史，这一直都很重要。所以，能够
ability to go to good places and away
去往其他地方的能力至关重要。 远离
from bad places. Um so that's part of
危险的地方。 嗯，这是其中的一部分
it. Um secondly,
。 其次，
building your financial strength is
增强你的财务实力非常
important which has to do with how you
重要，这与你的
earn, spend and save. That will
收入、支出和储蓄方式息息相关。 这将
determine the amount. And then what you
决定金额。 然后，你可以
do with that amount is invest. And so
用这笔钱进行投资。 所以，
how you invest
你的投资方式也很
uh is also important.
重要。
So if you have your financial ability
所以，如果你有足够的经济能力，
and you can make the move and then you
可以做出改变，并且
have knowledge
了解正在
you know about what's happening
发生的事情，
so that you can change things. Those are
那么你就可以改变现状。 这些就是
the things you need. So on that first
你需要的东西。 所以，
point about a smart rabbit having three
关于聪明的兔子有三个
holes,
洞的第一点，
is it therefore
那么，
a better decision at this point in time
此时此刻，
to not to not buy a house? Because a lot
不买房是不是更好的决定呢？ 因为很多
of people end up buying a house and
人最终都会买房，把
anchors them to to a place and it means
他们束缚在一个地方，这意味着
that they then have to pay into a
他们之后就必须偿还
mortgage. So a lot of lot of the
抵押贷款。 所以，
financial advice most of us have growing
我们大多数人在成长过程中得到的很多理财建议
up is when you get enough money to buy a
都是，当你攒够钱
house, move in, pay that mortgage for 25
买房时，搬进去，然后偿还25
years. But if I'm in a new economy, in a
年的抵押贷款。 但如果我身处一个新的经济体、一个
new world, and flexibility and the
新的世界，那么灵活性以及随时
ability to get up and go and move is
出发、四处走动的能力就具有
there's there's uh value to that.
价值。
&gt;&gt; The ability to move capital matters. And
资金流动能力至关重要。
if you look at history, this has been an
纵观历史，这一直是一个
important consideration. Yes. So it
重要的考量因素。 是的。 所以这很
matters. So if you're nailing yourself
重要。 所以，如果你把自己束缚
down and that's your primary capital and
住，而那又是你的主要资本，并且
it's nailed down there, then that's does
它被牢牢地固定在那里，那么这确实会
limit your flexibility. And on the point
限制你的灵活性。 至于
of earning, spending, and saving, wonder
赚钱、花钱和储蓄，想想
what you you're a you're a a father,
你作为一位父亲，
aren't you?
是不是该怎么想呢？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。   在
the current world, where where they
当今世界，您会给孩子哪些关于赚钱的建议？他们
should set up their shop, the skills
应该在哪里开店？哪些技能
that are most valuable to acquire, the
最有价值？有哪些
technologies, the we talked about the US
技术？我们之前讨论过，美国
being a place to one of the better
是
places to build your career for all the
发展事业的好地方之一，原因正如
reasons you described. Well, that's,
您所描述的那样。 嗯，
you know, that's kind of like the
你知道，这有点像
particular that you asked me for. That's
你问我的那个具体问题。 那比
below the level of the higher level.
更高一级的水平要低。
Okay. The higher level is I have a
好的。 更高层次的是我坚持
principle. Make your work and your
原则。 让你的工作和你的
passion the same thing. And don't forget
热情融为一体。 别忘了还有
about the money part.
钱这部分。
Okay? If you make your work and your
好的？ 如果你把工作和
passion the same thing so that you're
爱好变成同一件事，
really enjoying your work, you'll have
真正享受工作，你就会拥有
an enjoyable satisfactory life and
快乐满足的生活，
you'll probably be better at your career
你的事业也会发展得更好，
that um as a result probably advance and
从而获得晋升
so on. So you have a happier life and
等等。 这样你就能拥有更幸福的生活，也更有
you will have a more probably a more
可能拥有更
successful life. But it is true that the
成功的人生。 但
careers that you choose will have
你选择的职业确实会对
financial implications.
经济状况产生影响。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And if you say, "I want to be a poet or
如果你说，“我想成为一名诗人或从事类似的
something along those lines." You better
职业。” 你最好
consider the financial implications of
考虑一下这会带来哪些经济影响
that. That doesn't mean that you have to
。 但这并不意味着你必须
go make a ton of money because I think
去赚很多钱，因为我
that that's I think a lot of people fall
认为很多人都会陷入
into that trap that they think the money
这种误区，他们认为金钱，
is um like vast amounts of money is vast
比如大量的金钱，就等同于巨大的
amounts of success. And that's not true.
成功。 那不是事实。
In other words, is your work and your
换句话说，你的工作和你的
passion the same thing? So, I think that
热情是一回事吗？ 所以，我认为能给
what brings people happiness is
人带来幸福的是
meaningful work and meaningful
有意义的工作和有意义的
relationships.
人际关系。
&gt;&gt; Okay? If you have meaningful work, you
好的？ 如果你有一份有意义的工作，你
know, that you're into and your, you
知道，你热爱这份工作，
know, your passion and your work's the
你的热情和你的工作是
same thing. And you have meaningful
一回事。 如果你拥有有意义的
relationships, whether through that work
人际关系，无论是在工作中
or beyond, you're going to have probably
还是工作之外，你很可能会拥有
a great life. Okay? And so, you have to
美好的人生。 好的？ 所以，你必须
keep that in mind. And it doesn't have
牢记这一点。 而且，
much correlation past a certain level of
超过一定金额后，这种相关性就不大了
money.
。
&gt;&gt; Uh it doesn't have much correlation with
嗯，这和你的财富多少并没有太大的相关性
money you have. And if you see studies
。 如果你查看
across societies and you'll see that
不同社会的研究，你会发现，
past that certain basic level, there's
超过某个基本水平之后，
money they have and how much happiness
人们拥有的金钱数量与
they have or well-being. Okay? that the
他们的幸福感或福祉之间就没有相关性了。 好的？ 在所有
societies and studies of happiness and
社会和关于幸福与
well-being is community. Do you have a
福祉的研究中，社区的相关性最高。 你有
sense of community? Do you have those
社区意识吗？ 你
around you who are your community?
身边有能让你感到归属感的人吗？
You'll live longer that way. You'll have
那样你会更长寿。 你会拥有
a more joyous life and it'll be a better
更快乐的生活，
outcome. But anyway, so thinking about
结果也会更好。 总之，
those things I think is important
我认为
&gt;&gt; based on your life cycle in this book
根据本书的原则，在你的人生旅程中思考这些事情很重要，它符合你的生命周期原则
principles your guided journey. create
。 制定自己的
your own principles to get the work and
原则，以获得
life you want. Do you think you have to
你想要的工作和生活。 你认为
play different games in different
在
seasons of your life cycle as it relates
人生的不同阶段，为了
to generating wealth? And what I'm
积累财富，是否需要采取不同的策略？ 我在
talking about here is really like risk
这里真正想说的是风险
profile um or what I should be
状况，或者说我应该
optimizing for. Should I be should I be
优化的方向。 我应该努力
trying to hang around with Ray Dalio or
和雷·达里奥保持联系，还是
should I be focusing on the job that
应该专注于
pays me the most?
收入最高的那份工作？
&gt;&gt; First of all, the answer is yes.
首先，答案是肯定的。
And the second question you asked the
至于你问的第二个问题，
answer is um that you should be around
答案是，你应该和那些最擅长
to teach you to operate by the the
教你如何操作的人在一起，通过
mentors and the learnings and so on. You
导师和学习等等。 你
should be around the best people and
应该和最优秀的人在一起，
when I say best people I mean people of
我所说的最优秀的人是指
good character and good capabilities.
品行端正、能力出众的人。
Okay. And uh so you should be around the
好的。 所以你应该和最
best not the job that pays you the most.
优秀的人在一起，而不是只做薪水最高的工作。
And I could explain why that is, but and
我可以解释为什么会这样，但是，是的
yes, in terms of that arc, you will play
，就这个弧线而言，你在人生的
it differently at different parts of
不同阶段会以不同的方式演绎它
your life cycle. So in the early part of
。 所以，在
your life cycle, what you're going to do
你人生的早期阶段，你要做的
is I mean the more learning and
就是尽可能多地学习和
experiencing is the most important thing
体验，这是
that you can do in the learning in the
你在
early part of your life cycle.
人生早期阶段所能做的最重要的事情。
It's like you're going to make your
就好像你要做出
choices. what direction am I going to be
选择一样。 我将朝着哪个方向前进等等
in and so on so forth. So learn. Okay,
。 所以要好好学习。 好的，这才是
that that's that's most important. And
最重要的。
then what you're at the end of your life
然后，当你走到人生的尽头时
cycle, you're pretty much relieved from
，你基本上就从这一切中解脱出来了
all of that. You're not going to be
。 你不用
working to earn, okay? You're going to
工作赚钱，明白吗？ 你将
be free of all of that. You're going to
摆脱这一切。 你会
have um and you have freedom of choices
拥有……，你有选择的自由
and so on. And you're going to be
等等。 你将会
thinking about transitioning. how do I
考虑转型。 我该如何
transition well-being or how do I
过渡到幸福阶段？或者我该如何
transition my wealth or how do I
过渡到财富阶段？或者我该如何
transition and so on you know that's
过渡到其他阶段等等，你知道，
that's where you are still learning is a
你仍在学习，这本身就是一种
joy but at the same time in terms of
乐趣，但同时，就
trying to accomplish it's not the same
努力实现目标而言，
at your late part of your life cycle as
在你人生的后期阶段与
it is in your early part of your life
在人生的早期阶段是不一样的。
cycle
所以我想问问你人生的早期
cycle and what the most important
阶段，以及你做出的最重要的
strategic or wealth generating decisions
战略性或创造财富的决定是什么？
you made that you would encourage
你会
encourage everybody to consider if their
鼓励大家思考，他们的
nature is aligned to yours.
本性是否与你的本性相符。
&gt;&gt; Okay. My nature was I hated school. I
好的。 我生性厌恶学校。 我
didn't like the whole thing of
不喜欢
remembering this and remembering this
记住这个、记住那个，
and then give it back to me and there
然后再把这些还给我，还有
were these uh you know history like
那些历史，比如
there's William the Conquer in 1066 and
1066年的征服者威廉，
what did he do and you know like all of
他做了什么，你知道，所有这些都是
that was what education represented. And
教育所代表的。
when I was um 12, a kid, I earned money
当我还是个孩子，12岁的时候，我靠打
with odd jobs like um I had a paper
零工赚钱，比如送报纸、割
route and um I mowed lawns and I caddied
草坪、当球童等等。我把当球童挣的钱
and I took my cadding money and when I
拿去投资，那时
was 12 I got everybody was talking about
12岁的我，每个人都在谈论
the stock market. So I put some money in
股票市场。 所以我把一些钱投入了
the stock market. I didn't know what I
股市。 我当然不知道自己在
was doing, of course, but I um I picked
做什么，但我……我选了……那只
um the stock that was the only stock I
股票是我唯一
ever heard of that was selling for less
听说过的、每股售价低于
than $5 a share. And my reasoning was I
5 美元的股票。 我的想法是，我
could buy more shares, so if it went up,
可以买入更多股票，这样如果股价上涨，
I could make more money. Okay, that was
我就可以赚更多钱。 好吧，那是
a stupid criteria, but it was a company
一个很愚蠢的标准，但那是一家
that was about to go bankrupt. And
即将破产的公司。
another company acquired it and it
另一家公司收购了它，
tripled in price. and I said, "I like
价格翻了三倍。 我说：“我喜欢
this game."
这个游戏。”
[Music]
[音乐]
So, I got I got hooked on the game. I'm
所以，我迷上了这款游戏。 我
still hooked on the game, right? So, I
仍然对这款游戏着迷，对吧？ 所以，我很
liked it. Okay. That that affected me.
喜欢。 好的。 这件事对我影响很大。
So, I barely got into uh CW Post College
所以，我勉强考上了 CW Post 学院，
and then I went to uh Harvard Business
然后去了哈佛商
School and that opened my eyes to the
学院，那里的一切都让我大开眼界，
world in in many ways because of who
因为那里的人，那里的氛围等等，
that, you know, the best and the
你知道，都是最优秀、最
brightest kind of thing. But I always
聪明的人。 但我一直都在进行
still traded markets because I always
市场交易，因为我一直都在
played the game. I could tell you
玩这个游戏。 我可以给你讲
stories. You want a couple of quick
故事。 你想听几个小
stories?
故事吗？
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So, I'm clerking on the floor of
好的。 所以，我在
graduating from college and in the
大学毕业后到去
and going to uh Harvard Business School.
哈佛商学院前的那个夏天，在纽约证券交易所做交易员。
And that is 197 the summer of 1971.
那是197年，也就是1971年的夏天。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. And on August 15th, 1971,
嗯。  1971 年 8 月 15 日，
Richard Nixon
理查德·尼克松在
gets on the television and says
电视上说，
that, you know, the promise that that
你们知道，之前承诺
you were going to be able to take your
你们可以用
paper money and go get gold, you can't
纸币兑换黄金，现在这个承诺不能兑现了，
do that and we're not we're going to cut
我们不会
off that off. He didn't say it in
停止这项承诺。 他虽然没有用
exactly those words, but money then was
这些话直接表达，但当时的货币就是
gold and what we think of as paper
黄金，而我们现在所认为的
money, fiat money was claims on the
纸币、法定货币，实际上是对黄金的索取权
gold. So I walked on the floor of the
。
New York Stock Exchange that summer and
那年夏天，我走进了纽约证券交易所，当时
I thought the market was going to go
我觉得股市会
down a lot and the market went up a lot
大幅下跌，结果股市却大幅上涨，
and I didn't understand why because I
我不明白为什么，因为我
never went through a devaluation before.
以前从未经历过股市贬值。
And I studied history and I found that
我研究过历史，发现
in March of 1933,
1933 年 3 月，
Roosevelt got on the radio and made the
罗斯福在广播中发表了
exact same announcement that you're not
完全相同的声明，说你们不会
going to get your gold and they're going
得到黄金，他们将
to print the money. And when you print a
印钞票。 当你大量印钞时
lot of money, you have that. Okay. So, I
，就会出现这种情况。 好的。 因此，我
learned that history of things that
了解到，了解那些
never happened in my lifetime before
在我有生之年从未发生过的历史事件
were important things to understand.
是非常重要的。
Okay. I went back then to Harvard
好的。 当时我回到哈佛
Business School two for two years and
商学院学习了两年，
and two years later as a result of all
两年后，由于
the printing of money and the oil shock
货币大量印发和石油危机，也就是
1973 oil shock and now because of my
1973年的石油危机，现在因为我的
background I'm head hired to be director
背景，我被
of commodities at a Wall Street
华尔街一家
brokerage firm.
经纪公司聘为大宗商品主管。
Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Which and then all sorts of things
然后，各种各样的事情就
happened. Um turbulence and so on so
发生了。 嗯，湍流等等
forth. That firm went broke. I went to
。 那家公司破产了。 我去了
another firm and I was uh rowdy. I
另一家公司，我在那里很吵闹。 我
wasn't your typical good employee, you
不是那种典型的乖员工，你
know, follow everything. And uh so I got
知道，那种事事都遵守规定的员工。 呃，所以我被
fired and that was in uh 1975
解雇了，那是在 1975 年，
and then I but uh clients all liked me
然后，呃，客户们都很喜欢我，
and for things and so they would pay me
因为他们愿意付钱给我提供
for advice and I continued to trade the
建议，我继续进行
markets and that's when I formed
市场交易，也就是在那时我创立了
Bridgewwater.
Bridgewater。
Okay.
好的。   那
&gt;&gt; And what
是1975年。
I just passed along Bridgewater 50 years
50年后，我才路过布里奇沃特
later.
。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So there's a journey there that
好的。 所以这是一段充满
has failures and successes and
失败、成功和经验
learnings. You know, I have a principle.
教训的旅程。 你知道，我坚持原则。
Pain plus reflection equals progress.
痛苦加上反思等于进步。
Okay? Your best learnings come from the
好的？ 痛苦中往往能学到最好的东西
pain. It's a message. Pay attention.
。 这是一条信息。 注意。
Learn how reality works and how to deal
了解现实的运作方式以及如何以
with it differently so you have
不同的方式应对现实，这样你就能拥有
better. And I learned that process. And
更好地应对现实的原则。 我学习了这个过程。 正是
from that process, my company
通过这个过程，我的公司
Bridgewwater became the largest hedge
Bridgewater 成为了世界上最大的对冲
fund in the world. Um, extremely
基金。 嗯，非常
successful,
成功，
&gt;&gt; managing how much?
管理着多少？
&gt;&gt; $150 billion. 1,500 people, $150
1500亿美元。  1500人，1500
billion.
亿美元。
&gt;&gt; And that's made you a very wealthy man.
那让你成了个非常富有的人。   这
&gt;&gt; And made me a very wealthy man, which by
让我成了个非常富有的人，顺便说一句，这
the way was not my intention.
并非我的本意。
Okay. I just wanted to play the game and
好的。 我只想玩游戏，也
to have meaningful work and meaningful
想从事有意义的工作，建立有意义的
relationships. That was paramount. But
人际关系。 这一点至关重要。 但碰巧那
it happened to be the game I played. If
正是我玩的游戏。 如果
you're good at the game, you make a lot
你游戏玩得好，就能赚很多
of money. And now I'm at a stage in my
钱。 现在我到了人生的一个阶段，
life where I'm I want to pass things
我想把一些东西传承下去
along. I need to pass things along,
。 我需要把事情传达出去，
right? So, hence the books, hence our
对吧？ 所以，才有了这些书，才有了我们的
conversation
对话，才有了现在的局面
&gt;&gt; and here we are. That's the life arc.
。 这就是人生轨迹。
But I learned a lot. And so that's the
但我学到了很多。 这就是
journey.
旅程。
&gt;&gt; I think B2B marketeers keep making this
我认为B2B营销人员一直在犯这个
mistake. They're chasing volume instead
错误。 他们追求的是数量而
of quality. And when you try to be seen
不是质量。 当你试图让
by more people instead of the right
更多的人看到你，而不是让合适的
people, all you're doing is making
人看到你时，你只会制造
noise. But that noise rarely shifts the
噪音。 但这种噪音很少能改变
needle. And it's often quite expensive.
现状。 而且通常价格相当昂贵。
And I know as there was a time in my
我知道，在我
career where I kept making this mistake
职业生涯的某个阶段，我不断犯这个错误，
that many of you will be making it, too.
你们中的许多人也会犯同样的错误。
Eventually, I started posting ads on our
最终，我开始在我们的
show sponsors platform, LinkedIn. And
节目赞助商平台 LinkedIn 上发布广告。
that's when things started to change. I
事情就是从那时开始发生变化的。 我
put that change down to a few critical
认为这种变化归因于几个关键
things. One of them being that LinkedIn
因素。 其中之一是，LinkedIn
was then and still is today the platform
当时是、现在仍然是
where decision makers go to not only to
决策者们
think and learn but also to buy. And
思考、学习和购买的平台。
when you market your business there,
当你在那里推广你的业务时，
you're putting it right in front of
你就直接把它摆在了
people who actually have the power to
真正有决定权的人面前
say yes. And you can target them by job
。 您可以按
title, industry, and company size. It's
职位、行业和公司规模进行精准定位。 这是
simply a sharper way to spend your
一种更有效地利用
marketing budget. And if you haven't
营销预算的方式。 如果你还没
tried it, how about this? Give LinkedIn
试过，那不妨试试这个？
ads a try. and I'm going to give you a
不妨试试LinkedIn广告。 我将给你
$100 ad credit to get you started. If
100美元的广告抵用金，帮助你起步。 如果
you visit linkedin.com/diary,
您访问 linkedin.com/diary，
you can claim that right now. That's
即可立即认领。 那是
linkedin.com/diary.
linkedin.com/diary。
Just for context, people don't like
简单来说，人们不喜欢
talking about money and I understand it,
谈论金钱，我理解这一点，
but you're a prolific philanthropist.
但你是一位慷慨的慈善家。
Also, Google says that your net worth is
此外，谷歌表示，你的净资产高达
in the tens of billions of dollars. And
数百亿美元。
I'm sure there's some people that have
我相信有些人点开
clicked on this conversation and aren't
这个对话后，并不
aware of the scale of wealth you built
了解你积累的财富规模，也不了解
up and the scale of Bridgewater Capital
桥水资本的规模，
and how prolific and famous it is in the
以及它在投资界的影响力和知名度
investing world. In that 50-year life
。 在你提到的50年人生
arc, one of the things you mentioned is
历程中，痛苦是其中之一
pain. All of us will encounter pain. And
。 我们每个人都会遭遇痛苦。
you said pain plus
你说的是痛苦加上
&gt;&gt; reflection.
反思。
&gt;&gt; Reflection equals progress. How have you
反思即进步。 你是如何
leared to deal with pain? You've had a
学会应对疼痛的？ 你
lot of pain in all facets of life
在生活的各个方面都经历了很多痛苦，
because you've lived the life arc um and
因为你经历了人生的种种磨难，而且这种磨难还在
you continue to. How what's the best
继续。
principle for dealing with pain?
应对疼痛的最佳原则是什么？
&gt;&gt; First of all, um to calm yourself down
首先，嗯，让自己冷静下来，集中注意力
and to get centered. Meditation has had
。 冥想
a big beneficial effect on my life. We
对我的生活产生了巨大的积极影响。 我们
can get into meditation in a minute of
可以花一分钟时间了解一下冥想是
how it has. But the ability to, you
如何进行的。 但是，你
know, in a sense calm yourself down
知道，在某种程度上，要能够让自己冷静下来，
and when the time is right to reflect on
并在适当的时候反思所
what's happened both to understand how
发生的事情，从而了解
reality works. You know, you want to be
现实是如何运作的。 你知道，你想成为
a hyper realist. I understand how
一个超级现实主义者。 我明白
reality works. Therefore, I need to do
现实是如何运作的。 因此，我需要
this under this set of circumstances,
在当前情况下做这件事，
which means developing principles. And
这意味着要制定原则。
so what I did when I would do that
所以，每当
anytime whenever I would think what what
我思考该怎么做的时候，
should I do whether painful or not I
无论痛苦与否，我
would pause reflect
都会停下来反思，
on you know what should I do if that
如果同样的事情再次发生，我该怎么办。我就是这样把
write down my principles and what I did
我的原则写下来的。
was I wrote down a lot of principles
我写下了很多原则，很多很多的
&gt;&gt; a lot of principles if this happens that
原则，比如如果发生这种情况，发生那种情况
happens and whatever and then so I wrote
等等。
these principles down and then I found
然后我发现，
that in investing
在投资领域，
um if I can computerize those
如果我能把这些
decision rules I could back test them
决策规则计算机化，我就可以进行回测，
see how they would have worked and so
看看它们是如何运作的
on. So I built systems, decision-making
等等。 所以我建立了系统，决策
systems. Um, computer would make
系统。 嗯，电脑会做出
decisions. So it was AI before LLMs, but
决定。 所以，人工智能早于法学硕士出现，但
it was AI to have decision-making
人工智能的作用是提供决策
criteria. So it would be like I I would
标准。 这就好比我
make a computer chess game that would
制作一个电脑象棋游戏，在
play while I was playing my mental chess
我进行脑力象棋
game, what moves we would make. And it's
比赛的时候，它会模拟我们接下来要走的棋步。 而且它是
completely automated and so on. But I'm
完全自动化的等等。 但我
what I'm trying to say is that
想说的是，
reflecting on how does reality really
反思现实的
work
运作方式
and what do I do when this happens to
以及当这种情况发生时我该怎么做，
that happens is the development of
是
principles and that has been invaluable
原则的形成，这非常宝贵，
and it also makes me see things
也让我以不同的视角看待事物，
differently because a lot of people um
因为很多人，嗯，
and if I didn't do this I would be
如果我不这样做，我就会
seeing almost as uh a blizzard of things
觉得各种事情像暴风雪一样向
coming at me
我袭来，而现在
I see everything as another one of
我把一切都看作是其中之一
those. So let let's say for example it
。 比如说，
it's a species. So it's like seeing okay
它是一个物种。 所以这就好比看到，好吧，
that's what kind of species is it and
这是什么物种，
how do I deal with that species? So it's
我该如何应对这个物种？ 所以，这只是其中之一，
one of those rather than just a lot of
而不是很多
things coming at me.
事情同时向我袭来。
&gt;&gt; Pattern recognition of
模式识别“是”
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But but let's say if you think of
。 但是，假设你想到的
a it's a duck.
是一只鸭子。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Okay.
好的。 好的。
&gt;&gt; Oh okay. It's a duck. How do I deal with
哦好的。 这是一只鸭子。 我该如何对付
a duck? Or it's a lion.
一只鸭子？ 或者它是一头狮子。
&gt;&gt; Okay, how do I deal with a lion?
好吧，我该如何对付狮子？   而不是
&gt;&gt; Rather than just a lot of things coming
很多事情同时涌来
at it. So this principle thinking and
。 所以这种原则性思维
seeing it that way had a big effect on
方式对
the quality of my decision making and
我的决策质量产生了很大的影响，这对我
and that helped.
很有帮助。
&gt;&gt; Two questions I had there is to become a
我当时有两个疑问：要成为一个
principal thinker I need to do more
主要思考者，我需要进行更多的
reflection, right? And then the other
反思，对吗？ 然后，另一个人会
&gt;&gt; think about how does how does the
思考：机器是如何运作的？
machine how does how does life how do
生命是如何运作的？
these things work? So that's what I
这些东西是如何运作的？ 这就是我的
mean. Okay.
意思。 好的。
&gt;&gt; And to write that down.
并把它写下来。
&gt;&gt; Uh yeah. Yeah. Write down your thoughts.
嗯，是的。 是的。 把你的想法写下来。
I find sometimes what I would do is I'd
我发现有时候我会用
uh dictate them into my iPhone.
我的 iPhone 把它们口述出来。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. I'd say no. Okay. Ah this is how
好的。 我觉得不行。 好的。 啊，这就是
when you're making a decision. Why did
做决定时的感觉。
you make that decision?
你为什么做出那个决定？
So, not just make a decision, but think
所以，不仅要做出决定，还要
about the criteria you're using to make
考虑你做决定的标准，
&gt;&gt; also my emotions, my trauma, my
以及我的情绪、我的创伤、我的不
insecurities, my anxiety,
安全感、我的焦虑，
&gt;&gt; right? And and you might say when
对吧？ 你可能会问，
reflecting on that, is that helpful? Is
反思一下，这有帮助吗？
that harmful?
这样做有害吗？
And what do I do about that? Like for
那我该怎么办？
example when what you're referring to is
例如，当你指的是
yes the um that the motions and the
动作、
things and all of those um we uh you
事物等等的时候，你
have to understand that that basically
必须明白，
the brain's got two parts to it right it
大脑基本上分为两部分，对吧？一部分是
part of your brain reasonable tries to
大脑的逻辑部分，它理性地尝试
reason things through and then which is
推理事物，也就是意识；另一部分是
conscious and then it has the
潜意识，也就是潜意识层面，它
subliminal that is really driving you
真正驱动着你。
and so when you can reflect okay how are
所以，当你能够反思“
my emotions entering into it what do I
我的情绪是如何融入其中的？我该怎么做？”等等，当
you know and so on and you can think and
你能够思考并
you can align that that's very powerful
调整这些想法时，这非常强大。顺便说一句，
and meditation by the way naturally does
冥想自然而然就能做到
that because what you do when you
这一点，因为你在
meditate and maybe a times come I should
冥想时所做的，也许有时候我应该
explain meditation okay how it works um
解释一下冥想是如何运作的。冥想是
what you do is it's a process process by
一个过程，在这个过程中，
which you sit quietly and you repeat in
你安静地坐着，在脑海中重复一个
your mind what is called a mantra which
叫做咒语的东西，它
is a sound that it's a word that has no
是一个没有
meaning. Let me say the most classic
意义的声音或词语。 让我举一个最经典的
example of that would be okay. So you're
例子吧。 所以你
quietly there and you go with your
静静地待在那里，随着
breath you go you know
呼吸，你知道，
like that but you need to be taught but
就像那样[音乐]，但你需要被教导，但
anyway I um and so when you're doing
无论如何，嗯，所以当你这样做的时候，
uh because your m is in your mind or
因为你的m在你的脑海里，或者
your mantra is in your mind you're not
你的咒语在你的脑海里，你就
able to have other thoughts.
无法有其他想法。
You'll see yourself wavering between
你会发现自己在
doing that and staying on the mantra and
这样做和坚持念诵咒语之间摇摆不定，
then having thoughts. Um but what and
然后又会冒出其他想法。 嗯，但是……
then you go back to your mantra. When
然后你又回到你的口头禅。 当
you are uh in the mantra a a lot then it
你长时间沉浸在咒语中时，它就会
disappears. The sound disappears and you
消失。 声音消失了，你
go into your subconscious mind. That's
进入了潜意识。 这就是
what they call transcending.
他们所说的超越。
meditation I do. And so you go there and
我练习的是超验冥想。 所以你到了那里，
you're not in a conscious state and
你既不是处于清醒状态，
you're not in a subcon unconscious
也不是处于潜意识无意识
state. You're in a conscious state. So
状态。 你处于清醒状态。 所以
it's subconscious state. It's not
这是一种潜意识状态。 即使
unconscious is you're sleeping.
睡着了，也不是无意识的。
Conscious is that you're awake like we
意识就是像我们一样处于清醒状态
are. You're in this. So it's a different
。 你参与其中。 所以情况不一样了
state. Like if you hear that noise, you
。 就像如果你听到那种声音，你
would hear that noise. It would be big.
就会听到那种声音。 那将会是件大事。
Not when you're sleeping. But when
睡觉的时候不会。 但当
you're in your subconscious state, then
你处于潜意识状态时，就会感到
it's relaxing.
放松。
uh it's helpful and this process helps
嗯，这很有帮助，这个过程有助于
to um bring your conscious state and
使你的意识状态和
your uncon subconscious state into
无意识的潜意识状态保持
alignment.
一致。
In other words, you recognize both and
换句话说，你既认识这两者，又能
it calms you down. It it's like the
安抚你的情绪。 就像
ninja in the ninja movies, you know,
忍者电影里的忍者一样，你知道，
they're fighting but they it seems in
他们在打斗，但动作看起来像是
slow motion. The camera shows them in
慢动作。 镜头以慢动作拍摄他们，
slow motion and they're doing whatever
他们就这样做着
they're doing along that. It kind of
他们正在做的事情。 它
makes you in that kind of state of mind
会让你进入那种心态，
so that you're dealing with what's
让你以那种
coming at you in that way. And so what
方式去应对即将发生的事情。 所以
you referred to is this um these things
你提到的这些事情，
that happen and how you deal with those
以及你如何处理这些事情，对
your decision-making.
你决策的质量来说真的非常重要。
&gt;&gt; How influential was transcendental
超验
meditation in your success?
冥想对你的成功有多大影响？
&gt;&gt; Oh, enormously successful. Enormously
哦，非常成功。 意义极其
significant. Ve very very significant.
重大。 非常非常重要。
In other words, that way of singing
换句话说，那种唱歌的方式
seeing things
看待事物，
&gt;&gt; and how often
以及它发生的频率，
&gt;&gt; and and by the way, there's you know
顺便说一句，你知道，
there's I I would say say there's a
我想说，有一种
serenity prayer. The serenity prayer is
宁静祷文。 平静祷文是：
God give me the serenity to accept that
上帝，请赐予我平静，去接受
which I can't control
我无法控制的事；
and give me the power to control that
赐予我力量，去控制我
which I can and the wisdom to tell the
能控制的事；赐予我智慧，去分辨这两者的
difference.
区别。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And so to how you approach these
好的。 所以，对于如何处理这些
things, we're talking about reflection.
事情，我们谈论的是反思。
You ask me reflection. Okay? If you can
你问我是否反思过。 好的？ 如果你能
reflect in that quality way, then you
以这种高质量的方式进行反思，那么你就能
deal with anything. And I've I've dealt
应对任何事情。 我已经处理过最
with uh the worst possible thing. Um I
糟糕的事情了。 嗯，我
lost a son. Okay? And I would have
失去了一个儿子。 好的？ 我宁愿
rather died. I would have rather lost
去死。 我宁愿失去
everything to lose my son. So it's the
一切，也不愿失去我的儿子。 所以这是
worst possible thing. and and then to
最糟糕的情况。 然后你就会
see what it did you know the damage and
明白它造成了什么后果，你知道它给
the harm from family terrible. Okay.
家庭带来的伤害有多么可怕。 好的。
Then to go through that with meditation
然后通过冥想、
with reflection and so on uh was
反思等等方式来经历这个过程，这非常
invaluable and people have their own
有价值。每个人都有自己的
challenges but to be able to do it that
挑战，但能够以这种
way I I really urge your audience I urge
方式进行，我真的强烈建议我的听众，我强烈建议
you to uh to learn that that's very
你们学习一下，这非常有
helpful. How how did that tragedy change
帮助。 那场悲剧是如何改变
your your perspective and your your
你对
principles in any way on life on on
生活、
happiness on success on all these things
幸福、成功以及你所写过的所有这些事物的看法和原则的
that you've written about?
？
&gt;&gt; Well, it's again I you know I go above
嗯，你知道，当我超越
it and um you reflect on the life arc
它，反思人生轨迹时，
and I realize at that higher level that
我意识到，在更高的层面上，
that's what the life arc is like. you
人生轨迹就是这样的。
you'll in in all my books there's this
在我的所有书中，你都会看到这个弧形，
this arcing here's a bigger version of
这个弧形，这里有一个更大的版本，嗯，是的，
it uh yeah there's this arcing okay I
这里有个弧形，好吧，我
don't know if you're camera sees that
不知道你的相机能不能拍到，
okay whatever it is and that's what life
好吧，不管它是什么，这就是
and evolution is like to me meaning you
我眼中生活和进化的样子，意思是你会
make advances
取得进步，
you will have setbacks
也会遇到挫折，
okay if you reflect Well, and you learn
好吧，如果你反思，你就会明白
how reality works and how you will deal
现实是如何运作的，以及你将如何应对
with it,
它，
you will get past that and go on. And
你就会克服困难，继续前进。 事实就是如此
that's just what it is. That's just the
。
way life is. And if you do that well,
生活就是这样。 如果你能做到这一点，
then that's your best possible life.
那么这就是你所能拥有的最好的生活。
&gt;&gt; Are you religious? Are you a religious
你信教吗？ 你是信教的
person?
人吗？
&gt;&gt; I'm not religious, but I'm spiritual.
我没有宗教信仰，但我有精神追求。
&gt;&gt; Okay. The Dalai Lama who I had the
好的。 我有幸
pleasure of meeting told me u and I I
见到的达赖喇嘛告诉我，我
agree with um that religions are
同意他的观点，宗教通常是
um a mix between superstitions
迷信
and spirituality. There's half of it is
和灵性之间的混合体。 其中一半是
that element that nobody knows but there
无人知晓的因素，另一半是
the way people should deal with each
人们应该如何
other. There is karma.
彼此相处。 世事有因果。
Okay. All religions
好的。 所有宗教都有“己所不欲，勿施于人”
unto you or what goes around comes
或“善有善报，恶有恶报”的说法，
around and then you get to the
然后你就会深入到具体
particulars. Okay. And it is true
细节。 好的。 的确，
that if we work well together
如果我们合作愉快，
that even little things I can do to help
即使是我能做的一些小事也
you can make a big difference in your
能对你的生活产生巨大的影响，
life and little things that you can do
而你能做的一些小事也能
to help me make a big difference in our
帮助我，从而对我们的生活产生巨大的影响
lives. And so it's practical and it is
。 所以它既实用又
also joyous.
令人快乐。
Okay, that creates a relationship. And
好的，这就建立了一种关系。
we talked earlier about how that
我们之前也讨论过，这种
meaningful relationship is like the
有意义的关系就像是
source of great happiness. But when you
幸福的源泉。 但是，当你
have a community and you do that, you
拥有一个社区并这样做时，你就会
have a better society. And almost all
拥有一个更美好的社会。 几乎所有
religions will tell you that there'll be
宗教都会告诉你，其中都包含这些
elements of those. And when I believe in
元素。 当我信仰
spirituality, what I also mean is uh
灵性时，我的另一个意思是，
we're all part of this greater hole.
我们都是这个更大宇宙的一部分。
Okay? We're all part of the greater
好的？ 我们都是这个更大
hole. And if you could see yourself as
黑洞的一部分。 如果你能把自己看作是
part of the greater whole and love the
更大整体的一部分，并热爱这个
greater whole uh and whatever that is
更大的整体，嗯，无论那是什么，
spirituality really okay and so I will
精神层面的东西，好吧，我会
go through my life arc okay and I will
经历我的人生轨迹，好吧，我会
die and I'm comfortable with that okay
死去，我对此感到坦然，
in that okay it's all part of the
好吧，这一切都是
greater whole you know na nature and
更大整体的一部分，你知道，自然，以及
whatever it is that's true I can't tell
任何它是什么，这是真的。我无法告诉
you about other things but I do believe
你其他的事情，但我确实相信
in the things I just told you
我刚才告诉你的那些。
&gt;&gt; when it comes to living a successful
说到成功的
life we've talked about having dreams
人生，我们谈到了拥有梦想、
and understanding your nature and
了解你的本性、
aspiring for things and then
渴望追求，以及
understanding reality which
理解现实，而
transcendental meditation is a great
超验冥想是一个很好的
mechanism and vehicle to do um and in
机制和途径。嗯，在
your in your book about a successful
你的书中，
life you talk about plus determination
你谈到了成功的人生，你还谈到了决心、决心和
hard work
努力。
if I want to be a successful
如果我想成为一个成功的
man or woman, how important do you think
人，你认为努力有多重要
hard work is?
？
&gt;&gt; Well, gives you power. It's very
嗯，这能赋予你力量。 这非常
important, right?
重要，对吧？
&gt;&gt; Some people some people, you know,
有些人，你知道，
&gt;&gt; I'm not saying they want to choose it,
我不是说他们想选择它，
but the ir the irony of things is
但讽刺的是，事情有
there are first order consequences and
第一层后果和
there are second order consequences.
第二层后果。
This is like a rule of life, okay? And
这是人生的一条准则，好吗？ 而且
most of the time the first order
大多数情况下，第一阶段的
consequences
后果（
whether they're likable or not
无论是否讨人喜欢）都会在
has the opposite second quarter second
第二季度产生相反的第二
order consequences. What I mean by that
阶段后果。 我的意思是，这
is like eating or exercising. Okay, eat
就像吃饭或锻炼一样。 好吧，吃
the foods you like.
你喜欢吃的食物吧。
Second order consequence is probably not
次级后果可能
going to be good. um you know I don't
不会好。 嗯，你知道我不想
want to exercise
锻炼，
um second order consequences won't be as
嗯，次级后果不会那么
good. Okay. Working hard which gives you
好。 好的。 努力工作会让你变得
strength. Where does strength come from?
强大。 力量从何而来？
I mean strength comes from working hard.
我的意思是，力量来自于努力。
So working hard will will give you
所以努力工作会给你
power.
力量。
Power will make things easier and make
权力会让事情变得更容易，让
things better. That's just the way it
事情变得更好。 事情就是这样
is.
。
and being open-minded while you do it.
同时保持开放的心态。
&gt;&gt; openminded to you.
对你来说，这是一种开放包容的态度。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I say uh the importance of being
。 我认为，保持
open-minded and assertive at the same
开放的心态和坚定的信念同样重要
time. Um I I
。 嗯，
I watch
我看着
people becoming so
人们如此
tied to their own opinions like this is
固执己见，这简直是
the greatest tragedy of mankind.
人类最大的悲剧。
The greatest transgen of mankind because
人类最大的缺陷在于，人们固执己见，固执己见
holding a strong opinion that is wrong
是错误的，而
if you were open to learning more. If
如果你愿意学习更多知识，你本可以更好地纠正它。 如果
you would said, "I want to be stress
你说：“我想接受压力
tested. I want my thinking to be stress
测试。我想让我的思维经受压力
tested. I want to make sure that I'm
测试。我想确保自己
making the better decision and so I'll
做出更好的决定，所以我愿意接受
be challenged. But a lot of people view
挑战。” 但很多人把
that challenging like a fight.
这种挑战看作是一场争斗。
It's not a fight. If somebody holds a
它不是争斗。如果有人持有
different opinion, it should prompt a
不同的观点，它应该激发你的
curiosity.
好奇心。
You know, I don't know. Am I wrong or is
你知道，我不知道。是我错了还是
they wrong? There's a 50% chance. I
他们错了？有50%的可能性。我
don't know. Maybe I'm wrong. So, it
不知道。也许是我错了。所以，它
should prompt curiosity and in exchange
应该激发你的好奇心，并促使你
to try to make sure that you're seeing
努力确保自己看到事情的
the whole picture and so on. But
全貌等等。但
subliminal instincts are I'm going to
潜意识里，人们会想“我要
stick with it and I'm going to have a
坚持己见，我要
fight. That's a problem
战斗”。这是一个问题，
&gt;&gt; because there's too much on the line for
因为对
so many people to
很多人来说，风险太大了，这种潜意识的想法就会滋生出来
&gt;&gt; it's subliminal. It's it's it just goes
。这归根结底还是源于人们把
intellectual challenge is a fight and
智力挑战当成一场争斗，
it's egotistical. You know, ego,
这是一种自负。你知道，自负驱使着人们认为“
I must be right.
我一定是对的”。
&gt;&gt; As an as an investor and entrepreneur,
作为一名投资者和企业家，
that's obviously particularly important
这很危险。 显然，这一点尤其重要，
because you're constantly dealing with
因为你得不断处理
your information and feedback, which you
信息和反馈，而你
need to be flexible. That was one of the
需要灵活应对。这是
two things that changed my
改变我人生
uh my my my whole direction and made me
方向并最终让我
successful. I I can explain it if you
成功的两件事之一。如果你想听，我可以解释一下
want.
。
79 and 80
1979年和1980年，
I had calculated that American banks had
我计算出美国银行
lent more money to foreign countries
借给外国的钱超过了
that they were going to be able to pay
它们能够
back and that we were going to have a
偿还的金额，我们将面临一场
debt crisis.
债务危机。这是一个
Very controversial point of view. In
极具争议的观点。
1982,
1982年8月，
Mexico defaulted on its debts and over
墨西哥债务违约，在
the next decade, many other countries
接下来的十年里，许多其他国家也相继违约，
did and it caused bank problems.
导致银行业出现问题。
However, at that time, I thought things
然而，当时我认为情况
were going to get bad and that was the
会变得很糟糕，而
1982.
1982年8月正是股市触底反弹的时候。
So, I couldn't have been more wrong.
所以，我的判断大错特错。
I lost money for me. I lost money for
我自己赔了钱，客户也赔了钱，
the clients. I lost money. I was so
我赔了钱。我
broke that I had to borrow $4,000 from
穷到不得不向父亲借4000美元
my dad to help to pay for family bills
来支付家庭账单，
because I was faced with the choice.
因为我面临着一个选择：
What am I going to do? And and do I do I
我该怎么办？我该怎么做？
go back to work on Wall Street, get a uh
回到华尔街工作，打个
tie, get on the train, and go back that
领带，坐上火车，然后继续做
which is again not in my nature or
那些不符合我本性的事情
whatever. And and two things changed me.
。有两件事改变了我。
First of all,
首先是反思。
um, I learned what we were just talking
嗯，我学会了我们刚才讨论的那些东西
about. I learned humility and fear of
。我学会了谦逊、害怕
being wrong and open-mindedness.
犯错和保持开放的心态。
So, I wanted the smartest people who
所以，我想要找到最聪明的人来
could I could find to stress test my
检验我的
opinions because I'm always realized I
观点，因为我始终意识到自己
could be wrong. And then I learned how
可能会犯错。然后，我学会了如何
to diversify my bets so that I could
分散投资，这样我就可以在
dramatically reduce my risk without
不降低收益的情况下大幅降低风险
reducing my returns. Okay, that was the
。好了，那是最
bottom. Okay, from that point all the
底层。从那时起，
way over that following those principles
遵循这些原则让
took me to the biggest hedge fund in the
我成为了世界上最大的对冲基金
world, the most successful and so on
，也是最成功的对冲基金，等等，
because I applied it to the markets,
因为我将这些原则应用到了市场中，
applied it to what we did and so on. So
应用到了我们的工作中等等。所以，
that notion of reflection and then how
反思的概念，以及如何
do you deal with what reality is like
应对现实，
and then you know okay the learn learn
然后你知道，学习彻底的
radical open-mindedness in other words
开放心态，换句话说，
and like there's a principle in the book
就像书中提到的一个原则，
you have to take in before you put out
你必须在发表意见或
or that um decision making is a two-step
做出决定之前先理解它。 这是一个两步
process first take in then decide. Okay.
流程：先吸收信息，再做决定。好的。
So, yes, open-mindedness.
所以，是的，保持开放的心态很重要。
your ability to decide. So, you still
这绝不会削弱你的决策能力。你仍然
have the freedom to decide, but it's
有决策的自由，但如果
crazy not to be open-minded.
不保持开放的心态就太不明智了。
&gt;&gt; You recognize that the biggest threat to
你要明白，对
good decision-m is harmful emotions. And
良好决策的最大威胁是负面情绪。而
that two-step process is first learn and
这个两步流程就是先学习，
then make the decision. Which is funny
再做决定。
because it sounds simple, but when you
这听起来很简单，但你这么一
said it, I think about all the worst
说，我就想起了
decisions I've ever made in business.
我在商业上做过的所有最糟糕的决定。
And I missed step one.
我都忽略了第一步。
I forgot to I forgot to take a minute
我忘了花点时间
and do the evidence gathering or the
收集证据或
like information gathering process.
信息。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, just smart people who care about
是啊，那些关心
your decision say stress test me.
你决策的聪明人会说，给我做压力测试。
&gt;&gt; Why don't we do that?
我们为什么不试试呢？
&gt;&gt; That ego
因为自负
and also instinct that that's a fight.
和本能是一场斗争。
&gt;&gt; Is there any advice you would give me on
你有什么建议能让我
becoming a better decision maker? So I
成为一个更好的决策者吗？我
have a fund, I have many businesses. Is
有一个基金，我有很多企业。有没有什么
decision maker that we haven't talked
我们还没讨论过的，关于如何成为一个更好的决策者的实用而简单的方法
about? Get smart people to interrogate
？让聪明人来审视
my thinking. Um, be open-minded.
我的想法。 嗯，要保持开放的心态。
&gt;&gt; I think we've talked about almost all of
我想我们几乎都讨论过了
them. Um, I think then you have to then
。嗯，我觉得接下来你必须
know about how to leverage yourself.
知道如何发挥自己的优势。
Okay. In other words, as you do more and
好的。换句话说，随着你做的事情越来越
more,
多，
uh, how do you do more and more when
嗯，当
your brain has a capacity limit, okay,
你的大脑容量有限，
in the day or the week, okay, you have
一天或一周只有一定时间的时候，你该如何做更多的事情呢？好的，你
to know how to do that.
必须知道该怎么做。
&gt;&gt; Is that focus or is that something?
是专注力吗？
&gt;&gt; No, no,
不，不，
&gt;&gt; no.
不。
It's knowing how to do it through
是知道如何通过他人来完成工作
others.
。
Okay. It's knowing how to pick others
好的。是知道如何挑选合适的人
and orchestrate. Well, it's like uh
并进行协调。嗯，就像
running a symphony or whatever. Okay.
指挥一个交响乐团一样。好的，
get the best players.
找到最优秀的成员。
Okay, when I say uh you know um good
好的，我说的是，你知道，好的
character and good capabilities and
品格和能力，并且要
orchestrate them well and then provide
好好协调他们，然后提供那种
that um that leverage like uh um when I
杠杆作用，比如，嗯，当我
was doing the most I had 30 direct
工作最多的时候，我有30个直接
reports
下属，
whatever the number is. So uh it the
不管具体数字是多少。所以，
process is how to get more out of a
关键在于如何让每一
minute or a day,
分钟或每一天都发挥更大的作用，而
not how to work harder, okay? It's how
不是如何更努力地工作，好吗？ 这就是如何
to leverage yourself. And you're going
发挥自身优势。而发挥
to leverage yourself by picking the
自身优势的关键在于选择
right people who you can trust. They're
值得信赖的人才。他们
not going to screw you. They're going to
不会坑害你，会维护
operate in your interest and they're
你的利益，并且
going to be capable. And so a lot of
能力出众。
people what you can do is you can deal
你可以和他们合作，
with them and then you can say like I I
比如你可以说，我
would deal with them on this 30 reports.
会负责处理这30份报告。
I'd have maybe um an hour meeting with
我可能每两周和他们开一次会，每次一个小时，然后他们就可以
go off and do things. And when you do
去做其他事情了。这样做，
that you can even find people who are
你甚至可以找到比
much better at things than you would be
你更擅长某些事情的人
if you did them. Because if you have
。因为如果你拥有
these different things, okay, you better
这些不同的资源，那就更好了，
because otherwise you don't have the
否则你就没有
capacity.
能力做到。作为一名企业家，
&gt;&gt; You have these two key challenges to to
你需要克服两大挑战：
find these great capable people that
找到这些能力出众、品格
have great character and then like bind
高尚的人才，然后把
them with the right culture to make sure
他们融入合适的企业文化，确保
that they do the best work,
他们能够做出最好的工作。
&gt;&gt; right? And and in other words, it's
换句话说，
through radical truthfulness and radical
通过彻底的真诚和
transparency.
透明，就能创造有意义的工作和人际关系。
&gt;&gt; Radical truthfulness and transparency.
彻底的真诚和透明。
&gt;&gt; Okay. First, if you can have um
首先，如果你能拥有
meaningful work and meaningful
有意义的工作。 建立有意义的
relationships, the people are on the
人际关系，让人们
mission with you.
与你并肩作战。
Wow, that's fantastic. But
哇，太棒了！但是
you you better be truthful and
你最好坦诚
transparent. That'll show that you're
透明。这能展现你的
honest and you better because you have
诚实，而且你最好如此，因为你必须
to get a truth including what people are
了解真相，包括人们的
bad at and how to deal with all those
缺点以及如何应对这些
things
问题，
&gt;&gt; and and most people hide them.
而大多数人都会隐藏这些缺点，
&gt;&gt; They don't bring them out into the open.
不会公开谈论。
Okay, they everybody's worried about
好吧，每个人都担心
hurting each other's feelings or you
伤害彼此的感情，或者你
know uh that and then so they're not
知道的，呃，就是这样，所以他们
honest with each other and and they're
彼此不坦诚，这就是我们之前
that's the barrier you we talked about
提到的障碍——
the barrier of disagreement there's it's
分歧的障碍。就是这样，
like that okay um you know uh I don't
好吧，你知道，呃，我不
know are you good at that or you're
知道你擅长处理分歧吗？或者你做得不好？
striking out if you're striking out and
如果你做得不好，那
what is it how do we deal with it you
我们该如何处理？你
better talk about that clearly because
最好把这些都说清楚，因为
you need to have an a team of players
你需要一支优秀的团队，
you know you have to work yourself so
你知道，你必须努力，这样
your team is an A team of players who
你的团队才能成为一支团结的优秀团队
are tight.
。
&gt;&gt; How did you do that at Bridgewater? How
你在布里奇沃特是怎么做到的？
did you make people honest?
你是如何让人们坦诚的？
&gt;&gt; Oh, well uh f first of all um I had a
哦，嗯，首先…… 我曾在
policy talk behind another person's back
别人背后私下讨论政策，
um critically. That happens three times,
嗯，这很关键。这种情况发生三次，
you're out. And then I would have
你就出局了。然后我会采取
radical transparency so everybody could
完全透明的方式，让所有人都能
see everything. So you could see why I'm
看到一切。这样你们就能明白我为什么
making decisions and I would reflect.
做决定，我也会反思。
But the main thing is you know you know
但最重要的是，你们要知道事情是否真的
if it's happening or not. Okay. And I
发生了。好吧。我
made that comfortable
营造了一种轻松的氛围，
because that's ordinarily uncomfortable.
因为这通常会让人感到不舒服。
We talked about the fact that there's an
我们讨论了这样一个事实：
intellectual you and there's an
你既有理性的一面，也有
emotional subliminal you. Okay. I made
感性的一面。好吧。我让
them understand like if I had a team a
他们明白，就像我有一个团队，一个
football team
足球队
&gt;&gt; and so on that this is going to be
等等，这样做
better for the team. is going to be
对团队有好处，
better for you and you'll have your
对你也有好处，你会得到
evolution because what do you want to
成长，因为你希望别人
have dishonesty? Do you want people to
说谎吗？你希望别人对
think one thing about you and really say
你的看法和实际说的完全
something different?
不同吗？
&gt;&gt; How is that going to work? So there's an
这怎么可能行得通？所以，理性的一面是，
okay we believe it and then also by
好吧，我们相信这一点，同时，
having the meaningful relationships. I
建立有意义的人际关系也很重要。我的
mean I'm not I don't force them. I
意思是，我不会强迫他们。我
create a culture of meaningful
创造了一种有意义的
relationships so that they have known
人际关系的文化，让他们
each other for a long time. They go go
彼此认识很久。他们会互相了解。 参加
to each other's parties or they go to
彼此的聚会，或者参加
there are funerals. There are baby
葬礼，参加婴儿
showers. There are these things. Not
派对等等。并不是
that anybody's f I created uh clubs. I
说我创建了什么俱乐部。我
said, "Any club that you want to create
说：“任何你想创建的俱乐部，只要
that has more than uh 20 people um
超过20人，
whatever it is up to $500 per half." So,
无论是什么，我都会支付一半的费用，最高不超过500美元。”所以，
so I don't care what it is. If it's play
我不在乎是什么。无论是打
softball or play chess or whatever it is
垒球、下棋，还是任何
that you're enjoying each other's
你们享受彼此陪伴的活动，
company or you want to go to ball games
或者你们想去看球赛什么的
or something, I don't care what it is.
，我都不在乎。
I'll pay for half up to that up to $500.
我会支付一半的费用，最高不超过500美元。
So I to nobody has obligations to or
所以，没有人有义务这样做，
something but if I have that kind of
但如果我能建立起这种
meaningful relationships so you can talk
有意义的关系，让你们可以
honestly with each other uh I found that
坦诚地交流，我觉得这
very helpful
很有帮助。
&gt;&gt; and you've built a famously built an
你建立了一个著名的、以创意为导向的
idea meritocracy which in my
精英制度，我的
understanding means where the best idea
理解是，这意味着公司最终会选出最好的创意，而不是仅仅
just your idea because you're the most
因为你是
powerful person in the business
公司里最有权势的人，所以你的想法就能胜出，对吧？我的意思是，
&gt;&gt; right I mean I want what do I want I
我想要什么？我
want the best idea to win This sounds
想要最好的创意。 这听起来很
simple but but again it's it's not how
简单，但事实并非如此，企业并非如此
businesses operate. One of the
运作。
fascinations I've always had is that
我一直很着迷的一点是，
when businesses get bigger and they have
当企业规模扩大，
more intellectual horsepower by I mean
智力资源更加雄厚时（我的意思是，
if you just added up how many brains
如果把他们拥有的脑力加起来），
innovative and it it feels like the the
创新能力有时反而会下降，感觉就像CEO们一样，
CEO
因为他们变得更加
bureaucratic and more fragmented.
官僚主义，更加分散。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。好吧
&gt;&gt; Okay. There's um I found it to be true
。我发现这是真的，
and it's wellestablished fact that if
而且这是一个公认的事实：当
you get a group of people past a certain
一个团队的规模超过一定
size which is 75 to 100 people
程度（75到100人）时，
um they don't know each other. Okay,
他们彼此就不熟悉了。
they they they start to become different
他们开始变得疏远，
and then you lose those relationships.
然后你就会失去这些关系。
You lose a lot and so on. I found it
你会失去很多东西等等。我发现这一点是
because uh um at the holiday season
因为，每年节日期间
every year, what I would do is I would
，我都会给
write everybody
每个人写
notes, long notes in their cards and I
贺卡，写很长的祝福语，并
gift for them. And when it got to be to
为他们挑选个性化的节日礼物。当人数达到
67 people, I remember the year, it broke
67人时，我记得有一年，我累得
my back. I mean, I I just couldn't do
腰都直不起来了。我的意思是，我真的做不到
it. Okay. And I realized that at that
。好吧。 那时我意识到，
point I was
我正在
going into another frame. Okay. And so
进入另一个框架。好的。所以，
it's a organizational reality that you
组织上的现实是，你
can keep that group and then what you
可以保留这个团队，然后你
have to do is then you have different
需要做的就是，你拥有不同的
those different areas and you have to
部门，你必须在
create cohesiveness between those
这些不同的部门之间建立凝聚力，建立
different and cohesiveness common
共同的
mission and how do you do that between
使命，而你该如何做到这一点呢？举个
that. So, like for example, when we
例子，以前我们举办
would have our holiday party where it
节日派对的时候，
used to be everybody would be, you know,
大家都会聚在一起，你知道，参加
sort of go in and you have a holiday
节日
party and everybody together, what I
派对，大家聚在一起。但我
found out is we had a big arena that we
发现，我们有一个很大的体育馆，我们会
would uh go to and I'd have both. I'd
去那里，我会把各个部门的人员安排
have okay um that department is in that
好，比如，那个部门在那个
area and whatever and then they come out
区域等等，然后他们出来，
and they all mingle together and so on.
大家互相交流等等。
So there's an organizational
所以，
thing that you've got to realize in
在
terms of culture and and management of
文化和管理方面，你必须意识到组织上的这个问题
that.
。
&gt;&gt; It's like villages in a city I guess
这就像城市里的村庄，我想，
like yeah you basically keep build the
你基本上就是不断地建设这些
villages and then
村庄，然后形成一个
&gt;&gt; good example city. Interesting. Okay.
好例子——城市。有意思。好的。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Our media company's at that exact
。我们媒体公司
point now. It's at it's at that 90 90
现在就处于这个阶段。它正处于……  90
odd people.
个人，大概 90 多个。
&gt;&gt; Okay. There you are.
好的。就是这样。
&gt;&gt; So when you said 75 to 100 I was like ah
所以当你说 75 到 100 人的时候，我就觉得，啊，
interesting.
有意思。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I was thinking about all the
是啊。我一直在想，为了
counteract some of those adverse effects
抵消
of the culture splintering or
文化分裂或
relationships breaking down. But I guess
人际关系破裂带来的一些负面影响，我现在应该做些什么。不过我想
you've described it there. Uh
你已经描述得很清楚了。嗯，
interesting. And I have to say one of
有意思。我必须说，
the things I found to be most I'm 33
我发现最重要的一点是……我今年 33 岁，
years old. I just turned 33 last week.
上周刚满 33 岁。
how often people say that hiring is the
人们总是说招聘是
most important thing. Yet when you look
最重要的事，这真是太疯狂了。然而，当你
at how what entrepreneurs are spending
看看创业者们把时间花在了什么地方
their time on, it's usually like the
，通常是
product, the marketing, etc. and it's
产品、市场营销等等，
cases if they're lucky on finding truly
如果他们幸运地找到了真正
exceptional people. They often just
优秀的人才，可能也就花一两个小时。他们通常只是把招聘
outsource it to someone else, the
外包给其他人，比如
recruitment team. When you think back
招聘团队。回想
through your career, how important was
你的职业生涯，
it to find truly exceptional people?
找到真正优秀的人才有多重要？
&gt;&gt; Of course. Well, I systemized it first
当然重要。首先，我把它系统化了
of all. Um I think that anything I do or
。嗯，我认为我做的任何事情，或者
one does can be systemized. So I would
任何人做的任何事情，都可以系统化。 我会
think what are the personalities, what
思考，我要招聘的人的性格如何，背景如何，有
I'm hiring, what are the choices, how do
哪些选择，
I specify it? And I've and I got it by
我该如何具体说明？我通过
also maintaining a lot of data with
维护大量的
people. There's um there's a TED talk I
人员数据来实现这一点。我做过一个TED演讲，
did that uh explains how like data uh
解释了数据是如何被广泛应用，
everybody's going around and they're
以及人们如何以
operating in a certain way. So I know
某种方式运作的。所以我了解
what people are like. If you know what
人们的性格。如果你了解人们的性格
people are like, you know what you can
，你就知道你可以
expect of them. And then I would then
对他们抱有什么样的期望。然后，我会用
say uh in a very data way, those people
数据来分析，那些
who are successful in these jobs have
在这些工作中取得成功的人具备
the following attributes
以下特质，这些特质
that would create a job specifications
可以构成
for that type of job. So I I knew that
该类型工作的职位描述。所以我知道，
in that type of job there would be that
在这类工作中，会存在
type of person I'm looking for.
我想要寻找的那种人。
&gt;&gt; Okay. what works they work okay data and
好的，哪些特质有效，哪些特质有效，好的，数据，
then I would find that would be my job
然后我就会找到我的职位描述。
spec and and so we had the systems and
所以我们有相应的系统，也
then we had some people who are
有一些人
responsible for doing that because
负责这项工作，因为
you're right it takes time how can I
你说得对，这需要时间，我怎么可能
interview all those people and so on but
面试所有人呢？等等，但
who can you trust and you're operating
谁值得信任，你又如何运作呢？
that way and then evaluation process
评估过程并
doesn't stop when you hire them okay the
不会在你录用他们之后就结束。
valuation process continues from that
评估过程会从那一刻起继续，
moment and you still learn more about
你会继续了解
what they're like and you do that same
他们，并重复这个
process and still think would I still
过程，思考我是否还会
have hired them and and if I wouldn't
录用他们。如果我一开始就没
have hired them you know in the first
录用他们，那么
place then they shouldn't be there and
他们就不应该在那里。
so I have a process and people people in
所以我有一套流程，而人是处于
process
发展过程中的，
&gt;&gt; do people change after a certain point
人们会在某个阶段发生变化吗？
so if you've hired someone in six months
如果你录用某人六个月
and 12 months and they haven't changed
或十二个月，他们没有改变，那么是否
is it worth giving them another year is
值得再给他们一年时间？是否
it worth a performance review
值得进行绩效评估？
&gt;&gt; I found out that
我发现
for me the big question mostly there
对我来说，最大的问题
were two big questions but um the big
有两个，但最大的
question is how do you adapt to my
问题是：你如何适应我的企业
culture
文化？
and that would take about 18 months to
这大约需要18个月的时间来
find out like can you speak honestly
了解，比如：你是否能坦诚地表达自己的想法？
about what can we have thoughtful
我们能否进行理性的
disagreement do you like this
讨论？你是否喜欢这种充满
challenged and all of this kind of thing
挑战的成长过程？等等。这种
that culture that' take about 18 months
文化大约需要18个月的时间。然后，
and then roughly speaking then learning
大致来说，了解一个
about the people their strengths and
人的优势和
weaknesses
劣势
would take 18 months two two years maybe
需要18个月到两年的时间，也许差不多是这样。这样
you know you could pretty much decide
你才能做出决定。
but always being open every day by day
但要始终保持开放的心态，
so nobody's surprised that you're always
这样就不会有人对你总是
talking about things you know how's it
谈论事情感到惊讶。你知道，最近怎么样？
&gt;&gt; make sure you keep what I'm about to say
请务必记住我接下来要说的话。
to yourself I'm inviting 10,000 of you
我邀请10000位朋友
to come even deeper into the diary of a
更深入地了解一位CEO的日常
CEO. Welcome to my inner circle. This is
。欢迎加入我的核心圈子。这是
a brand new private community that I'm
一个全新的私人社群，我即将向
launching to the world. We have so many
全世界推出。我们这里有很多
incredible things that happen that you
你
are never shown. We have the briefs that
从未见过的精彩内容。我们有
are on my iPad when I'm recording the
我录制对话时iPad上的简报，
conversation. We have clips we've never
有从未公开过的片段，
released. We have behind the scenes
有
conversations with the guest and also
与嘉宾的幕后对话，还有
the episodes that we've never ever
从未
released and so much more. In the
发布过的节目等等。在这个
circle, you'll have direct access to me.
圈子里，你可以直接联系到我。你
You can tell us what you want this show
可以告诉我们你希望这个节目是什么样子
to be, who you want us to interview, and
，你想让我们采访谁，以及
the types of conversations you would
你希望我们进行哪些类型的对话
love us to have. But remember, for now,
。但请记住，目前
we're only inviting the first 10,000
我们只邀请前10000名
people that join before it closes. So,
加入者，之后名额将关闭。所以，
if you want to join our private closed
如果你想加入我们这个私密的封闭式社群，请尽快联系我们。
community, head to the link in the
社区成员请点击
description below or go to
下方说明中的链接或访问
daccircle.com.
daccircle.com。如今，
leading a business. New skills are
领导企业正值一个激动人心的时代。新技能
constantly being invented and ones that
层出不穷，
didn't exist a few months ago are now
几个月前还不存在的技能如今却
all of a sudden essential. Our team at
突然变得至关重要。Flight
Flight Story thrives on staying ahead of
Story 团队始终致力于走在
emerging tech and innovation. So
科技和创新前沿。因此，
whenever we need to plug into those
每当我们需要运用那些面向
skills of the future like vibe coding,
未来的技能，例如氛围编码、
AI agent development, generative engine
人工智能代理开发、生成式引擎
optimization, all of the technical
优化，以及
things we've talked about on the show
我们在节目中讨论过的所有技术时，我们都会选择
before, we always go to the same place,
同一个平台
which is Fiverr, our show sponsor, and
——Fiverr。Fiverr 是我们的节目赞助商，也是那些面向
the place where that future focused
未来的
talent quietly shows up before the rest
优秀人才悄然涌现的地方，往往在其他人意识到之前就已经出现
of the world catches on. Their
。他们的
freelancers are reliable, high
自由职业者可靠、
performing, and also highly vetted. And
高效，并且都经过严格筛选。
you'll find them in over 750 categories.
你可以在超过 750 个类别中找到他们。Fiverr
Fiverr isn't just for quick jobs. We use
不仅仅适用于短期项目。我们
their talent more on complex long-term
更多地将他们的人才用于复杂的长期
projects, ones that require an expert to
项目，这些项目需要专家全权
take charge. And you can tap into
负责。你可以
tomorrow's talent at fiverr.com/diary.
在 fiverr.com/diary 上找到未来的优秀人才。
And for 10% off your first order, use
首次注册还可享受 10% 的折扣。 顺序，使用
code diary. AI is um a bit of an alien
代码日志。人工智能就像一个外星人，
that seems to have entered the room um
似乎闯入了房间，
and has is going to change more almost
并将改变几乎
every every industry. Great.
所有行业。太好了。是的。
Yeah.
我不知道你是不是在讽刺。
&gt;&gt; No. Truly, if you are um working with
不。真的，如果你能与
it, controlling it, if it's a good
它合作，控制它，如果它是一个
partner to be able to get a lot of
能够获得巨大
leverage, it's truly fantastic. As I
优势的好伙伴，那它真的很棒。就像我之前
said in almost everything I did, we had
说的，在我做的几乎所有事情中，我们都有
the criteria, we had the systemized.
标准，我们有系统化的流程。
Would you do that? Would you not do
你会这样做吗？你不会这样做吗
that? How do you know how does reality
？你怎么知道现实是如何
work? What are the principles? And and
运作的？原则是什么？
so it's a fantastic leveraging like I
所以，就像我描述的那样，这是一个非常棒的杠杆作用
described. You know, I would make the
。你知道，我会把
decision-making model like the computer
决策模型做成电脑
chess game that would make it. Well, now
象棋游戏，这样它就能……嗯，现在
it's better than uh ever those those
它比以往任何时候都好，
resources. So it leverages you
利用了这些资源。所以它能
enormously.
极大地利用你。那么，
&gt;&gt; What about having a strong middle? We
拥有一个强大的中间派呢？我们
talked about having the strong sort of
讨论过拥有一个强大的
economic political middle.
经济政治中间派。
&gt;&gt; Political middle. Yeah. Yeah.
政治中间派。是的。是的。
&gt;&gt; Is it going to drive inequality?
它会加剧不平等吗？
&gt;&gt; Yes. It's going that's like all good
是的。它正在……就像 一切都很好，就像
like all things. going to be um it has
所有事物一样。嗯，它
good things and bad things and we were
有利有弊。我们刚才在
talking let's say first about managing
讨论，比如说，首先是关于管理。
and doing that I think in managing and
我认为，在管理方面，
knowing what people are like and how
了解人们的性格和行为方式，将会
they're all it's going to be very
非常
valuable
有价值，
mostly very valuable in terms of
尤其是在
changing um there'll be uh a limited
改变方面。嗯，
number of winners and a bunch of losers
赢家数量有限，而输家众多。
and um I think it's going to create much
嗯，我认为这将造成
greater polarity which as we're seeing
更大的两极分化，正如我们
um through the system the ways that we
通过这个系统所看到的，正如我们之前
talked about you know that top 1 to 10%
讨论的那样，前1%到10%的人
benefiting a lot and that you know so
获益良多，
that will be a dividing
这将会成为一种分裂的
uh force I think
力量。我认为，
with robotics accelerating at the speed
随着机器人技术以
of of light with optimist and Tesla and
光速发展，Optimist、特斯拉以及
all the things they're doing and all
所有
these other companies humanoid robots
其他公司正在研发的人形机器人，
and then with artificial intelligence
再加上人工智能领域
having trillions of dollars plowed into
投入了数万亿美元并
it and accelerating. We're in this crazy
加速发展，我们目前正处于疯狂的
boom at the moment. With these two
繁荣时期。这两者的
things combining, you're going to be
结合，将使我们能够
able to have a humanoid robot who that
拥有一个……
can navigate human spaces, but is also
它能自由穿梭于人类空间，而且
smarter than I am. Lawyers, accountants,
比我聪明得多。律师、会计师，还有
uh lots of people in the medical
很多医疗
profession. Why would you why would one
行业的人。
need them if we had a humanoid robot
如果我们拥有一个比
that is smarter than all of us and has a
我们所有人都聪明、拥有
PhD and everything? Well, we will not
博士学位等等的人形机器人，为什么还需要他们呢？嗯，正如你所说，我们确实不需要
need a lot of those jobs for the reasons
很多这样的工作了
that you're saying. Okay. And then the
。好的。那么
question is what our society does
问题来了，我们的社会该如何应对？
&gt;&gt; and what do you think we do in such a
你认为在这样的世界里我们该如何生存
world?
？
unfortunately. Um
不幸的是，我认为我们一直在争论我们应该做什么。嗯，
but as I say I I don't think we have
但正如我所说，我认为我们仍然无法
escaped a world where most people to
摆脱这样一个世界：为了
have a healthy society most people have
拥有一个健康的社会，大多数人必须
to be productive
富有生产力
and prosperous. I don't I I think people
且生活富裕。我认为人们
need to be now certainly there and there
现在肯定需要这样做，而且
certainly needs to be a redistribution
肯定需要一项再分配
policy. I don't think that's just a
政策。我认为这不仅仅是
redistribution of money policy because
重新分配金钱的政策，因为
uselessness and money may not be a great
无用和金钱可能不是一个好的
combination.
组合。
So I think that you have that has to be
所以我认为这个问题必须
figured out and the question is whether
解决，问题是
we're too fragmented to figure that out
我们是否因为过于分裂而无法找到解决方案
and agree on it and I'm worried about
并达成共识，我对此感到担忧。
that.
真是个
&gt;&gt; Interesting times. Is there any
有趣的时代。
historical precedence for this in your
你们的历史中是否有过类似的先例？
view? Someone that knows history. Is
呃？ 懂历史的人。
something like AI and robotics
人工智能和机器人技术
converging?
融合的历史先例吗？
&gt;&gt; Well, um
嗯，
through
通过
um evolution,
进化，
we have gone from a period of time which
我们已经从被
was called the dark ages or the
称为黑暗时代或
agricultural age in which um basically
农业时代的时期发展到了现在，在那个时期，基本上
there was land. it's agricultural and so
只有土地。 它以农业为主，
on and people were treated they were
等等，人们的待遇
essentially like oxen most people and
基本上和牛一样，大多数人都是如此。
then there were the landowners who were
然后是地主，也就是
the nobles and then there were the
贵族，然后是
royalty who uh were the families that
皇室，也就是
control most things and so on and then
控制大部分事务的家族等等。后来，随着
printing press there became more
印刷术的发明，人们获得了更多的
knowledge
知识，
um uh more intelligence and we see an
智力也得到了提升。我们看到了一种
evolution in which um you start to see
演变，在这个演变过程
industrial revolutions in which machines
中，新的时代出现了，新的思想出现了，权力也发生了变化。我不会带你回顾整个历史，但你会开始看到，个人可以足够聪明来赚钱。于是，你迎来了探索时代和工业革命，机器
replaced people and it's almost like
取代了人。这几乎就像机器
they first replaced them physically that
首先在物理上取代了人，
um in other words they didn't have they
换句话说，他们不再像牛一样干活了，
were not like oxen doing the thing so
所以
you get a tractor or something and and
你得到了拖拉机之类的东西。
it's almost like from the body up in
这几乎是从身体层面向上发展到
terms of the mind and so you've seen
思维层面。所以你看到了
that evolution through time and the rise
随着时间的推移，
of intelligence in its various forms go
各种形式的智力发展经历了
through this arc of rising in
一个上升的弧线，
intelligence and now you see that
现在你看到
intelligence
智力比什么都
matters more than anything. Okay? It
重要。 好的？ 它
matters more than money. It matters more
比金钱更重要。 这比什么都重要，
than anything because intelligence will
因为智力会
attract people among those with money to
吸引有钱人
invest in them in the development of
投资发展
that. And so we have seen this arc
它。 所以我们看到，
through history develop in that way,
历史的进程就是这样发展的，
right? And we've seen people replaced.
对吧？ 我们看到人员被替换了。
Now the question is as we get higher and
现在的问题是，随着我们
higher in thinking, okay, whether we've
思维方式的不断提升，我们是否已经
run out of capacity to shift or whether
丧失了转型的能力，或者
we're just going to be totally replaced.
我们是否会被彻底取代。
Our muscles have been totally replaced,
我们的肌肉已经被完全取代了，
but okay, as this is happening, our best
但是，好吧，随着这种情况的发生，我们最好的
thinking may be totally replaced and
思维方式也可能被完全取代，
we're going to have to deal with that
我们将不得不面对这个
question.
问题。
&gt;&gt; Are you hopeful?
你抱有希望吗？
&gt;&gt; I'm excited.
我很兴奋。
I think it all comes down to human
我认为这一切都归结于
nature. Okay. I'm excited in that.
人性。 好的。 我对此感到兴奋。
Fast forward, make the most of it, jump
快进，充分利用，抓住机会
on it. Woo! You know, I'm excited. I've
。 哇！ 你知道吗，我很兴奋。 我
also watched uh the evolution of
还观察过物种的进化
species.
。
Almost all species have come and gone
几乎所有物种都
for certain reasons and they uh one of
因为某些原因而出现又消失，其中一个
the reasons that they come have come and
原因
gone is because almost their strengths
是，它们的优势
are not in all respects great strengths.
并非在所有方面都是巨大的优势。
you can use these things, intelligence
你可以利用这些智慧，
to your detriment.
反而害了自己。
And I believe that um the things that
而且我认为，
these technologies and so on bring us
这些技术等等给我们带来的东西
while very important, it extends life
虽然非常重要，比如延长寿命等等，
expectancy and all of that
但所有这些
is not import as important as human
都不如人性重要
nature.
。
And so if you were to go back in time
那么，如果我们回到过去，
and we're at different societies, do you
处于不同的社会时期，你会选择
have happier societies? Is the
更幸福的社会吗？
well-being greater?
幸福感更高了吗？
Okay. So you can go 50 years ago and you
好的。 所以，如果你回顾 50 年前，你
might say the well-being is greater 50
可能会说 50 年前人们的幸福感更高
years ago. Not in all ways, not in in
。 并非所有方面都如此，
many ways the technologies and the
很多方面技术及其带来的
consequences of those are much better,
后果都好得多，
but you may have had a better life. And
但你的生活可能会更好。
it's human nature of how people are
这就是人与人之间
going to deal with each other. So I
相处之道的人性。 所以我
think the real question is can people
认为真正的问题是人们能否
rise above
超越
this and and which it goes back to the
这种境况，而这又回到了
spirituality question. Can people then
精神层面的问题上。 人们能否
rise above it so that they think of the
超越这种局限，转而考虑
collective good and they think of you
集体利益，思考
know collectively how do we make the
如何共同创造
best and also karma you know in other
最佳结果，以及因果报应？换句话说，他们能否意识到，
words um the realization that if I help
如果我以对
you in ways that can be so simple for me
我来说非常简单的方式
to help you make such a big difference
帮助你，就能对你
in your life and you do the same and we
的生活产生巨大的影响，而你也同样如此，我们就能建立
have win-win relationships it'll be good
双赢的关系，那当然很好。
but if we don't do that And I worry
但如果我们不这样做，我就担心
about human nature and I worry about
人性，也担心
this process,
这个过程，
&gt;&gt; especially when you've got geopolitical
尤其是在地缘政治
tensions. And
紧张局势下。 这
&gt;&gt; it's because of human nature.
是因为人性使然。
&gt;&gt; I've had a lot of conversations on the
我在
podcast about AI and I just can't seem
播客节目中就人工智能进行了很多讨论，但我似乎始终无法
to get to my own solid conclusion about
得出自己确切的结论，
this because when I look at human
因为
nature, as you say, I see greed, I see
正如你所说，当我审视人性时，我看到的是贪婪、
power, hunger, status.
权力、饥饿和地位。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Some problems you just just accept
。 有些问题你只能接受这样一个
the fact that you may not be able to be
事实：你可能无法
confident about a prediction in the
对未来的预测充满信心
future. So, it'll always be a question
。 所以，这始终是个问题，你
and just get on with the fact of using
只需要继续前进，找到
it for yourself in the best way that
最适合自己的使用方法
works for you.
。
&gt;&gt; That's what I'm doing. We have a closing
我就是这么做的。
tradition on this podcast where the last
本播客有个结尾的传统，上一任主持人会给下一任主持人
leaves a question for the next not
留下一个问题，而下一任主持人并不
knowing who they're leaving it for. You
知道这个问题是留给谁的。 你
know this person um because I've seen
认识这个人，因为我见过
you with them. Um the question they left
你和他们在一起。 他们留给
for you is what is a book or books that
你的问题是：
you've recommended or gifted more than
你推荐或赠送过的书籍中，哪一本或哪些书比
others and why? can't say your own but
其他书籍更多？为什么？ 我不能说你自己的，但是
&gt;&gt; right
嗯，
&gt;&gt; um there are three books
有三本书，
there's a book on evolution written by
一本是理查德·道金斯写的关于进化论的书，
uh river from
呃，好像
Eden I think it's called then a book by
叫《伊甸园之河》，然后是威尔·
Will and Ariel Durant which are the
杜兰特和阿里尔·杜兰特写的书，他们
maybe the greatest historians
可能是
in time and it's called lessons from
历史上最伟大的历史学家，书名叫《
history it's a very short book. I think
历史的教训》，这是一本很短的书。 我想应该是
it's 104 pages. They wrote massive
104页。 他们撰写了大量
amounts about 5,000 years of history and
关于五千年历史
so on. And they sort of condense their
等等的著作。 他们将
lessons, lessons from history.
历史教训浓缩起来。
And then um
然后是
Joseph Campbell's The Hero's Journey.
约瑟夫·坎贝尔的《英雄之旅》。   他是
&gt;&gt; Is it the the hero with a thousand
千
faces?
面英雄吗？
&gt;&gt; Yes, that's it.
对，就是这样。
&gt;&gt; Hero with a thousand faces.
千面英雄。
&gt;&gt; And why Dawkins book? Why did you say
为什么是道金斯的书？ 你为什么会
that one? Oh, he understands evolution.
这么说？ 哦，他懂进化论。
Everything is evolving. Okay. All
万物皆在变化。 好的。 所有
species. Man is one of 10,000 species.
物种。 人类是全球一万个物种之一。
I mean, and they're and they're all
我的意思是，它们的
structured similarly. There's a
结构都很相似。 它具有一定的
structure. They they you know, like um
结构。 它们，你知道，就像
two eyes, a brain that has a structure
两只眼睛，一个有结构的脑子
to it. Um that and the same parts of the
。 嗯，就是
brain. There's the cereum, the
大脑的那些部分。 这里有大脑半球、
cerebellum, the prefrontal cortex.
小脑和前额叶皮层。
there's this structure that makes you
这种结构会让你以
think differently and and so on. There's
不同的方式思考等等。 这是
evolution. There's all evolution. So,
进化的过程。 一切都是进化的结果。 所以，
it's not just limited to um human
这不仅仅局限于人类
evolution or what humans are like. It's
进化或者人类的本质。 这是
the force of evolution. Man is only um
进化的力量。 人类，或者说
mankind's only about 200,000 years old.
人类的历史，只有大约20万年。
That's in history that's short.
那是一段很短的历史。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And and the species and all
好的。 而且，所有
species evolve. Okay. And it's very
物种都会进化。 好的。 这很
interesting. So that's And you know
有意思。 所以，你知道，这就是
that's what his books are about and you
他的书的主题，而且
know I think they're very good
我认为它们非常好。
&gt;&gt; and Joseph Campbell's the hero's journey
约瑟夫·坎贝尔的英雄之旅，
the hero with it's it's about human
英雄与它，是关于
nature and and the evolution of life and
人性、生命的演变以及
the life journey that we're talking
我们正在谈论的人生旅程
about.
。
&gt;&gt; What I find so interesting Ray is how
雷，我觉得你最有趣的地方在于，
you draw on principles from other
你如何从其他
domains whether it's from nature or
领域（比如
biology as you were talking about there
你刚才提到的自然或生物学）汲取原理，并将之运用到
to tie into your work in business and
你的商业、
investing and everything else and life
投资以及其他一切与生活
and happiness. And it really says
和幸福相关的工作中。 这让
something to me about
我意识到，要想
curious in order to be successful in my
在我的叙事领域取得成功，就必须更加博采众长，保持广泛的好奇心
more
。 是的。 我只是觉得，我……我不……
that to me maybe too much of a
对我来说，这或许是一种过于
specialist kind of mentality but the
专业化的思维方式，但
things if you want to understand how
如果你想了解
reality works. Um you can't say I'm
现实是如何运作的，那么世界就是与这些事物相互关联的。 嗯，你不能说我只会
going to be just a specialist.
成为一名专家。
I mean these are all affected by each
我的意思是，这些事情都是相互影响的
other.
。
&gt;&gt; Thank you so much for write writing
非常感谢您撰写
these books. They are iconic and uh the
这些书籍。 它们堪称经典，而
YouTube videos that explain these these
解释这些书籍的 YouTube 视频也堪称
books are iconic. I don't know who you
经典。 我不知道你们
have on your team that makes the
团队里谁负责制作
animations and pulls it all together.
动画和把所有东西整合起来。
But not only is the content so important
但这些内容之所以如此重要，不仅是
because they are principles, so they're
因为它们是原则，所以能够
enduring through time, but they're so
经受住时间的考验，而且还因为它们对
unbelievably accessible to all people of
所有年龄段的人来说都非常容易理解
all ages. And if if you if people
。 如果有人
haven't read this book, I'd be shocked.
还没读过这本书，我会很惊讶。
But um all of these books are fantastic.
但是，嗯，这些书都很棒。
The this book, Principles by Ray Dalia,
这本书是雷·达利亚的《原则》，
which I'm going to link all of them
我会在下面附上所有相关链接，
below for anyone that wants to read
供有兴趣阅读的人参考
them. I suggest you read them all, um
。 我建议你把它们都读一遍，它们
will be formative in your life, even if
会对你的人生产生深远的影响，即使
you're not interested in business or
你对商业或投资不感兴趣，
investing because as as it says on the
因为正如
book, they're principles and the the
书中所说，它们阐述的是原则，而
economy affects us all in ways that we
经济以我们可能无法理解的方式影响着我们所有人
might not understand. We're all trying
。 我们都在努力
to be successful or happy in our own
追求成功或幸福
right. And that that's interwoven into
。 而这一点贯穿了
all of these books. So, thank you. I
所有这些书籍。 所以，谢谢。 我
hope you write more books. Well, and
希望你能写更多书。 嗯，
thank you because yeah, I'm at a stage
谢谢你，因为是的，我正处于人生的一个阶段
in my life, this is a symbiotic
，这是一种互惠互利的
relationship otherwise we wouldn't be
关系，否则我们就不会在
here. Okay. And my um my benefit is that
这里了。 好的。 我的好处是
I want to pass along these things and
我想把这些东西传承下去，
we're doing it together. And I have
我们正在一起做这件事。 我
found and it's joyous to me to know that
发现，
these things have made a big difference
这些事情给
in people's lives. People come up to me
人们的生活带来了巨大的改变，这让我感到非常高兴。 人们走过来对我
and they say, "Thank you for the
说：“谢谢
difference you've made." And you know,
你带来的改变。” 你知道，
at this stage in my life, that's what I
在我人生的这个阶段，这就是我
want to do.
想做的事。
&gt;&gt; I think that's an understatement. I
我觉得这还是轻描淡写了。 我
think it's had a profound impact. In
认为这产生了深远的影响。
fact, every person I know, all of my
事实上，我认识的每个人，我所有的
best friends have taken something from
好朋友，都从
your work which has had a profound
你的作品中有所收获，这些收获
impact on their decision-m which has led
对他们的决定产生了深远的影响，并
them to be happier in some way. And when
在某种程度上让他们变得更快乐。 当
I told my friends that I was
我告诉我的朋友们我要
interviewing you, I'm interviewing 16
采访你的时候，我告诉他们，在接下来的一个月里，我将
people while I'm in New York over the
在纽约采访 16 个人
over the next month. When I told my
。 当我告诉我的
friends, my best friends in the world,
朋友们，我最好的朋友们，
that I'm interviewing you, all of them
我要采访你的时候，他们都让
were telling me to pass on a message of
我转达
thanks because there's something in one
谢意，因为
of these books that's helped them. And
这些书中的某些内容对他们有所帮助。
they're all young people in that first
他们都是正处于
season of their life. And there's
人生最初阶段的年轻人。
there's something in all of these books
所有这些书中都蕴含着某种东西，它
that's um pushed them closer to their
推动他们走向
success and their happiness. So, thank
成功和幸福。 所以，我
you for on behalf of me because you've
代表我感谢你，因为你
had a profound impact on me. But thank
对我产生了深远的影响。 不过，谢谢
you.
你。
&gt;&gt; Thank you for giving me that joy.
谢谢你带给我这份快乐。
You know that. Thank you.
你知道的。 谢谢。
&gt;&gt; I really really mean that. Thank you so
我真的非常非常认真。 非常感谢你
much, Ray.
，雷。
[Music]
[音乐]